<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<content key="memory-scriptures" lang-original="en" lang-translated="es" last-updated="2020-02-15" last-updated-by="Jason McNeill" last-updated-by-email="vrtjason@gmail.com" created="2018-09-29" created-by="Jason McNeill" created-by-email="vrtjason@gmail.com">
	
	<phrase id="1" desc="title">
		<original>
			Memory Scriptures
		</original>
		<translated>
			Escrituras Para Memorizar
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="2" desc="">
		<original>
			
		</original>
		<translated>
			“Más bien, honren en su corazón a Cristo como Señor. Estén siempre preparados para responder a todo el que les pida razón de la esperanza que hay en ustedes.”
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="3" desc="">
		<original>
			
		</original>
		<translated>
			1 Pedro 3:15
		</translated>
	</phrase>


	<phrase id="4" desc="">
		<original>
		</original>
		<translated>
			Sesión 1
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="5" desc="">
		<original>
			"For I know the plans I have for you," declares the LORD, "plans to prosper you and not to harm you, plans to give you hope and a future."
		</original>
		<translated>
			Porque yo sé muy bien los planes que tengo para ustedes — afirma el Señor —, planes de bienestar y no de calamidad, a fin de darles un futuro y una esperanza.
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="6" desc="">
		<original>
			Jeremiah 29:11
		</original>
		<translated>
			Jeremías 29:11
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="7" desc="">
		<original>
			But seek first his kingdom and his righteousness, and all these things will be given to you as well.
		</original>
		<translated>
			Más bien, busquen primeramente el reino de Dios y su justicia, y todas estas cosas les serán añadidas.
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="8" desc="">
		<original>
			Matthew 6:33
		</original>
		<translated>
			Mateo 6:33
		</translated>
	</phrase>


	<phrase id="9" desc="">
		<original>
		</original>
		<translated>
			Sesión 2
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="10" desc="">
		<original>
			To the Jews who had believed him, Jesus said, "If you hold to my teaching, you are really my disciples. Then you will know the truth, and the truth will set you free."
		</original>
		<translated>
			Jesús se dirigió entonces a los judíos que habían creído en él, y les dijo: —Si se mantienen fieles a mis enseñanzas, serán realmente mis discípulos; y conocerán la verdad, y la verdad los hará libres.
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="11" desc="">
		<original>
			John 8:31-32
		</original>
		<translated>
			Juan 8:31-32
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="12" desc="">
		<original>
			I can do everything through him who gives me strength.
		</original>
		<translated>
			Todo lo puedo en Cristo que me fortalece.
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="13" desc="">
		<original>
			Philippians 4:13
		</original>
		<translated>
			Filipenses 4:13
		</translated>
	</phrase>


	<phrase id="14" desc="">
		<original>
		</original>
		<translated>
			Sesión 3
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="15" desc="">
		<original>
			"Come, follow me," Jesus said, "and I will make you fishers of men."
		</original>
		<translated>
			«Vengan, síganme —les dijo Jesús—, y los haré pescadores de hombres».
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="16" desc="">
		<original>
			Mark 1:17
		</original>
		<translated>
			Marcos 1:17
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="17" desc="">
		<original>
			A new command I give you: Love one another. As I have loved you, so you must love one another. By this all men will know that you are my disciples, if you love one another.
		</original>
		<translated>
			»Este mandamiento nuevo les doy: que se amen los unos a los otros. Así como yo los he amado, también ustedes deben amarse los unos a los otros. De este modo todos sabrán que son mis discípulos, si se aman los unos a los otros».
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="18" desc="">
		<original>
			John 13:34-35
		</original>
		<translated>
			Juan 13:34-35
		</translated>
	</phrase>


	<phrase id="19" desc="">
		<original>
		</original>
		<translated>
			Sesión 4
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="20" desc="">
		<original>
			Peter replied, 'Repent and be baptized, every one of you, in the name of Jesus Christ for the forgiveness of your sins. And you will receive the gift of the Holy Spirit.
		</original>
		<translated>
			—Arrepiéntase y bautícese cada uno de ustedes en el nombre de Jesucristo para perdón de sus pecados —les contestó Pedro—, y recibirán el don del Espíritu Santo.
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="21" desc="">
		<original>
			Acts 2:38
		</original>
		<translated>
			Hechos 2:38
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="22" desc="">
		<original>
			Rejoice in the Lord always. I will say it again: Rejoice!
		</original>
		<translated>
			Alégrense siempre en el Señor. Insisto: ¡Alégrense!
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="23" desc="">
		<original>
			Philippians 4:4
		</original>
		<translated>
			Filipenses 4:4
		</translated>
	</phrase>


	<phrase id="24" desc="">
		<original>
		</original>
		<translated>
			Sesión 5
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="25" desc="">
		<original>
			The soul who sins is the one who will die. The son will not share the guilt of the father, nor will the father share the guilt of the son. The righteousness of the righteous man will be credited to him, and the wickedness of the wicked will be charged against him.
		</original>
		<translated>
			Todo el que peque merece la muerte, pero ningún hijo cargará con la culpa de su padre, ni ningún padre con la del hijo: al justo se le pagará con justicia y al malvado se le pagará con maldad.
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="26" desc="">
		<original>
			Ezekiel 18:20
		</original>
		<translated>
			Ezequiel 18:20
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="27" desc="">
		<original>
			But even if we or an angel from heaven should preach a gospel other than the one we preached to you, let him be eternally condemned!
		</original>
		<translated>
			Pero, aun si alguno de nosotros o un ángel del cielo les predicara un evangelio distinto del que les hemos predicado, ¡que caiga bajo maldición!
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="28" desc="">
		<original>
			Galatians 1:8
		</original>
		<translated>
			Gálatas 1:8
		</translated>
	</phrase>


	<phrase id="29" desc="">
		<original>
		</original>
		<translated>
			Sesión 6
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="30" desc="">
		<original>
			Jesus replied: "Love the Lord your God with all your heart and with all your soul and with all your mind." This is the first and greatest commandment. And the second is like it: "Love your neighbor as yourself."
		</original>
		<translated>
			—"Ama al Señor tu Dios con todo tu corazón, con todo tu ser y con toda tu mente" —le respondió Jesús—. Este es el primero y el más importante de los mandamientos. El segundo se parece a este: "Ama a tu prójimo como a ti mismo".
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="31" desc="">
		<original>
			Matthew 22:37-39
		</original>
		<translated>
			Mateo 22:37-39
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="32" desc="">
		<original>
			This is to my Father's glory, that you bear much fruit, showing yourselves to be my disciples.
		</original>
		<translated>
			Mi Padre es glorificado cuando ustedes dan mucho fruto y muestran así que son mis discípulos.
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="33" desc="">
		<original>
			John 15:8
		</original>
		<translated>
			Juan 15:8
		</translated>
	</phrase>


	<phrase id="34" desc="">
		<original>
		</original>
		<translated>
			Sesión 7
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="35" desc="">
		<original>
			Then Jesus came to them and said, "All authority in heaven and on earth has been given to me. Therefore go and make disciples of all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father and of the Son and of the Holy Spirit, and teaching them to obey everything I have commanded you. And surely I am with you always, to the very end of the age."
		</original>
		<translated>
			Jesús se acercó entonces a ellos y les dijo: —Se me ha dado toda autoridad en el cielo y en la tierra. Por tanto, vayan y hagan discípulos de todas las naciones, bautizándolos en el nombre del Padre y del Hijo y del Espíritu Santo, enseñándoles a obedecer todo lo que les he mandado a ustedes. Y les aseguro que estaré con ustedes siempre, hasta el fin del mundo
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="36" desc="">
		<original>
			Matthew 28:18-20
		</original>
		<translated>
			Mateo 28:18-20
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="37" desc="">
		<original>
			For the Son of Man came to seek and to save the lost.
		</original>
		<translated>
			Porque el Hijo del hombre vino a buscar y a salvar lo que se había perdido.
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="38" desc="">
		<original>
			Luke 19:10
		</original>
		<translated>
			Lucas 19:10
		</translated>
	</phrase>


	<phrase id="39" desc="">
		<original>
		</original>
		<translated>
			Sesión 8
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="40" desc="">
		<original>
			And let us consider how we may spur one another on toward love and good deeds. Let us not give up meeting together, as some are in the habit of doing, but let us encourage one another — and all the more as you see the Day approaching.
		</original>
		<translated>
			Preocupémonos los unos por los otros, a fin de estimularnos al amor y a las buenas obras. No dejemos de congregarnos, como acostumbran hacerlo algunos, sino animémonos unos a otros, y con mayor razón ahora que vemos que aquel día se acerca.
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="41" desc="">
		<original>
			Hebrews 10:24-25
		</original>
		<translated>
			Hebreos 10:24-25
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="42" desc="">
		<original>
			If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just and will forgive us our sins and purify us from all unrighteousness.
		</original>
		<translated>
			Si confesamos nuestros pecados, Dios, que es fiel y justo, nos los perdonará y nos limpiará de toda maldad.
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="43" desc="">
		<original>
			1 John 1:9
		</original>
		<translated>
			1 Juan 1:9
		</translated>
	</phrase>


	<phrase id="44" desc="">
		<original>
		</original>
		<translated>
			Sesión 9
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="45" desc="">
		<original>
			See to it that no one misses the grace of God and that no bitter root grows up to cause trouble and defile many.
		</original>
		<translated>
			Asegúrense de que nadie deje de alcanzar la gracia de Dios; de que ninguna raíz amarga brote y cause dificultades y corrompa a muchos;
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="46" desc="">
		<original>
			Hebrews 12:15
		</original>
		<translated>
			Hebreos 12:15
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="47" desc="">
		<original>
			Obey your leaders and submit to their authority. They keep watch over you as men who must give an account. Obey them so that their work will be a joy, not a burden, for that would be of no advantage to you.
		</original>
		<translated>
			Obedezcan a sus dirigentes y sométanse a ellos, pues cuidan de ustedes como quienes tienen que rendir cuentas. Obedézcanlos a fin de que ellos cumplan su tarea con alegría y sin quejarse, pues el quejarse no les trae ningún provecho.
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="48" desc="">
		<original>
			Hebrews 13:17
		</original>
		<translated>
			Hebreos 13:17
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<!--

	<phrase id="" desc="">
		<original>
			
		</original>
		<translated>
			
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="true">
			<original>
				
			</original>
			<translated>
				
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="" desc="">
		<original>
			
		</original>
		<translated>
			
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	-->

</content>
