<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<scripture key="acts-2-36-47" lang="en" version="niv" edition="1984">
	<passage title="Acts 2:36-47" book="Acts" book-en="Acts">
		<chapter number="2" number-en="2">
			<verse number="36" number-en="36">
				"Therefore let all Israel be assured of this: God has made this Jesus, whom you crucified, both Lord and Christ."
			</verse>
			<verse number="37" number-en="37">
				When the people heard this, they were cut to the heart and said to Peter and the other apostles, "Brothers, what shall we do?"
			</verse>
			<verse number="38" number-en="38">
				Peter replied, "Repent and be baptized, every one of you, in the name of Jesus Christ for the forgiveness of your sins. And you will receive the gift of the Holy Spirit.
			</verse>
			<verse number="39" number-en="39">
				The promise is for you and your children and for all who are far off — for all whom the Lord our God will call."
			</verse>
			<verse number="40" number-en="40">
				With many other words he warned them; and he pleaded with them, "Save yourselves from this corrupt generation."
			</verse>
			<verse number="41" number-en="41">
				Those who accepted his message were baptized, and about three thousand were added to their number that day.
			</verse>
			<verse number="42" number-en="42">
				<p class="scripture-heading">
					The Fellowship of the Believers
				</p>
				They devoted themselves to the apostles' teaching and to the fellowship, to the breaking of bread and to prayer.
			</verse>
			<verse number="43" number-en="43">
				Everyone was filled with awe, and many wonders and miraculous signs were done by the apostles.
			</verse>
			<verse number="44" number-en="44">
				All the believers were together and had everything in common.
			</verse>
			<verse number="45" number-en="45">
				Selling their possessions and goods, they gave to anyone as he had need.
			</verse>
			<verse number="46" number-en="46">
				Every day they continued to meet together in the temple courts. They broke bread in their homes and ate together with glad and sincere hearts,
			</verse>
			<verse number="47" number-en="47">
				praising God and enjoying the favor of all the people. And the Lord added to their number daily those who were being saved.
			</verse>
		</chapter>
	</passage>
</scripture>

<!--
			<verse number="" number-en="">
				
			</verse>
			<verse number="" number-en="">
				<p class="scripture-heading">
					Heading text
				</p>
			</verse>
-->
