<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<scripture key="acts-9-1-22" lang="en" version="niv" edition="1984">
	<passage title="Acts 9:1-22" book="Acts" book-en="Acts">
		<chapter number="9" number-en="9">
			<verse number="1" number-en="1">
				<p class="scripture-heading">
					Saul's Conversion
				</p>
				Meanwhile, Saul was still breathing out murderous threats against the Lord's disciples. He went to the high priest
			</verse>
			<verse number="2" number-en="2">
				and asked him for letters to the synagogues in Damascus, so that if he found any there who belonged to the Way, whether men or women, he might take them as prisoners to Jerusalem.
			</verse>
			<verse number="3" number-en="3">
				As he neared Damascus on his journey, suddenly a light from heaven flashed around him.
			</verse>
			<verse number="4" number-en="4" jesuswords="true">
				He fell to the ground and heard a voice say to him, "<span class="jesuswords">Saul, Saul, why do you persecute me?</span>"
			</verse>
			<verse number="5" number-en="5" jesuswords="true">
				"Who are you, Lord?" Saul asked. "<span class="jesuswords">I am Jesus, whom you are persecuting,</span>" he replied.
			</verse>
			<verse number="6" number-en="6" jesuswords="true">
				"<span class="jesuswords">Now get up and go into the city, and you will be told what you must do.</span>"
			</verse>
			<verse number="7" number-en="7">
				The men traveling with Saul stood there speechless; they heard the sound but did not see anyone.
			</verse>
			<verse number="8" number-en="8">
				Saul got up from the ground, but when he opened his eyes he could see nothing. So they led him by the hand into Damascus.
			</verse>
			<verse number="9" number-en="9">
				For three days he was blind, and did not eat or drink anything.
			</verse>
			<verse number="10" number-en="10" jesuswords="true">
				In Damascus there was a disciple named Ananias. The Lord called to him in a vision, "<span class="jesuswords">Ananias!</span>" "Yes, Lord," he answered.
			</verse>
			<verse number="11" number-en="11" jesuswords="true">
				The Lord told him, "<span class="jesuswords">Go to the house of Judas on Straight Street and ask for a man from Tarsus named Saul, for he is praying.</span>
			</verse>
			<verse number="12" number-en="12" jesuswords="true">
				<span class="jesuswords">In a vision he has seen a man named Ananias come and place his hands on him to restore his sight.</span>"
			</verse>
			<verse number="13" number-en="13">
				"Lord," Ananias answered, "I have heard many reports about this man and all the harm he has done to your saints in Jerusalem.
			</verse>
			<verse number="14" number-en="14">
				And he has come here with authority from the chief priests to arrest all who call on your name."
			</verse>
			<verse number="15" number-en="15" jesuswords="true">
				But the Lord said to Ananias, "<span class="jesuswords">Go! This man is my chosen instrument to carry my name before the Gentiles and their kings and before the people of Israel.</span>
			</verse>
			<verse number="16" number-en="16" jesuswords="true">
				<span class="jesuswords">I will show him how much he must suffer for my name.</span>"
			</verse>
			<verse number="17" number-en="17">
				Then Ananias went to the house and entered it. Placing his hands on Saul, he said, "Brother Saul, the Lord — Jesus, who appeared to you on the road as you were coming here — has sent me so that you may see again and be filled with the Holy Spirit."
			</verse>
			<verse number="18" number-en="18">
				Immediately, something like scales fell from Saul's eyes, and he could see again. He got up and was baptized,
			</verse>
			<verse number="19" number-en="19">
				and after taking some food, he regained his strength. 
				<p class="scripture-heading">
					Saul in Damascus and Jerusalem
				</p>
				Saul spent several days with the disciples in Damascus.
			</verse>
			<verse number="20" number-en="20">
				At once he began to preach in the synagogues that Jesus is the Son of God.
			</verse>
			<verse number="21" number-en="21">
				All those who heard him were astonished and asked, "Isn't he the man who raised havoc in Jerusalem among those who call on this name? And hasn't he come here to take them as prisoners to the chief priests?"
			</verse>
			<verse number="22" number-en="22">
				Yet Saul grew more and more powerful and baffled the Jews living in Damascus by proving that Jesus is the Christ.
			</verse>
		</chapter>
	</passage>
</scripture>

<!--
			<verse number="" number-en="">
				
			</verse>
			<verse number="" number-en="">
				<p class="scripture-heading">
					Heading text
				</p>
			</verse>
-->
