<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<scripture key="acts-2" lang="en" version="niv" edition="1984">
	<passage title="Acts 2" book="Acts" book-en="Acts">
		<chapter number="2" number-en="2">
			<verse number="1" number-en="1">
				<p class="scripture-heading">
					The Holy Spirit Comes at Pentecost
				</p>
				When the day of Pentecost came, they were all together in one place.
			</verse>
			<verse number="2" number-en="2">
				Suddenly a sound like the blowing of a violent wind came from heaven and filled the whole house where they were sitting.
			</verse>
			<verse number="3" number-en="3">
				They saw what seemed to be tongues of fire that separated and came to rest on each of them.
			</verse>
			<verse number="4" number-en="4">
				All of them were filled with the Holy Spirit and began to speak in other tongues as the Spirit enabled them.
			</verse>
			<verse number="5" number-en="5">
				Now there were staying in Jerusalem God-fearing Jews from every nation under heaven.
			</verse>
			<verse number="6" number-en="6">
				When they heard this sound, a crowd came together in bewilderment, because each one heard them speaking in his own language.
			</verse>
			<verse number="7" number-en="7">
				Utterly amazed, they asked: "Are not all these men who are speaking Galileans?
			</verse>
			<verse number="8" number-en="8">
				Then how is it that each of us hears them in his own native language?
			</verse>
			<verse number="9" number-en="9">
				Parthians, Medes and Elamites; residents of Mesopotamia, Judea and Cappadocia, Pontus and Asia,
			</verse>
			<verse number="10" number-en="10">
				Phrygia and Pamphylia, Egypt and the parts of Libya near Cyrene; visitors from Rome
			</verse>
			<verse number="11" number-en="11">
				(both Jews and converts to Judaism); Cretans and Arabs — we hear them declaring the wonders of God in our own tongues!"
			</verse>
			<verse number="12" number-en="12">
				Amazed and perplexed, they asked one another, "What does this mean?"
			</verse>
			<verse number="13" number-en="13">
				Some, however, made fun of them and said, "They have had too much wine."
			</verse>
			<verse number="14" number-en="14">
				<p class="scripture-heading">
					Peter Addresses the Crowd
				</p>
				Then Peter stood up with the Eleven, raised his voice and addressed the crowd: "Fellow Jews and all of you who live in Jerusalem, let me explain this to you; listen carefully to what I say.
			</verse>
			<verse number="15" number-en="15">
				These men are not drunk, as you suppose. It's only nine in the morning!
			</verse>
			<verse number="16" number-en="16">
				No, this is what was spoken by the prophet Joel:
			</verse>
			<verse number="17" number-en="17" scripturequote="true">
				<span class="scripturequote">'In the last days, God says, I will pour out my Spirit on all people. Your sons and daughters will prophesy, your young men will see visions, your old men will dream dreams.</span>
			</verse>
			<verse number="18" number-en="18" scripturequote="true">
				<span class="scripturequote">Even on my servants, both men and women, I will pour out my Spirit in those days, and they will prophesy.</span>
			</verse>
			<verse number="19" number-en="19" scripturequote="true">
				<span class="scripturequote">I will show wonders in the heaven above and signs on the earth below, blood and fire and billows of smoke.</span>
			</verse>
			<verse number="20" number-en="20" scripturequote="true">
				<span class="scripturequote">The sun will be turned to darkness and the moon to blood before the coming of the great and glorious day of the Lord.</span>
			</verse>
			<verse number="21" number-en="21" scripturequote="true">
				<span class="scripturequote">And everyone who calls on the name of the Lord will be saved.'</span>
			</verse>
			<verse number="22" number-en="22">
				Men of Israel, listen to this: Jesus of Nazareth was a man accredited by God to you by miracles, wonders and signs, which God did among you through him, as you yourselves know.
			</verse>
			<verse number="23" number-en="23">
				This man was handed over to you by God's set purpose and foreknowledge; and you, with the help of wicked men, put him to death by nailing him to the cross.
			</verse>
			<verse number="24" number-en="24">
				But God raised him from the dead, freeing him from the agony of death, because it was impossible for death to keep its hold on him.
			</verse>
			<verse number="25" number-en="25" scripturequote="true">
				David said about him: <span class="scripturequote">'I saw the Lord always before me. Because he is at my right hand, I will not be shaken.</span>
			</verse>
			<verse number="26" number-en="26" scripturequote="true">
				<span class="scripturequote">Therefore my heart is glad and my tongue rejoices; my body also will live in hope,</span>
			</verse>
			<verse number="27" number-en="27" scripturequote="true">
				<span class="scripturequote">because you will not abandon me to the grave, nor will you let your Holy One see decay.</span>
			</verse>
			<verse number="28" number-en="28" scripturequote="true">
				<span class="scripturequote">You have made known to me the paths of life; you will fill me with joy in your presence.'</span>
			</verse>
			<verse number="29" number-en="29">
				Brothers, I can tell you confidently that the patriarch David died and was buried, and his tomb is here to this day.
			</verse>
			<verse number="30" number-en="30">
				But he was a prophet and knew that God had promised him on oath that he would place one of his descendants on his throne.
			</verse>
			<verse number="31" number-en="31">
				Seeing what was ahead, he spoke of the resurrection of the Christ, that he was not abandoned to the grave, nor did his body see decay.
			</verse>
			<verse number="32" number-en="32">
				God has raised this Jesus to life, and we are all witnesses of the fact.
			</verse>
			<verse number="33" number-en="33">
				Exalted to the right hand of God, he has received from the Father the promised Holy Spirit and has poured out what you now see and hear.
			</verse>
			<verse number="34" number-en="34" scripturequote="true">
				For David did not ascend to heaven, and yet he said, <span class="scripturequote">'The LORD said to my Lord: "Sit at my right hand</span>
			</verse>
			<verse number="35" number-en="35" scripturequote="true">
				<span class="scripturequote">until I make your enemies a footstool for your feet."'</span>
			</verse>
			<verse number="36" number-en="36">
				Therefore let all Israel be assured of this: God has made this Jesus, whom you crucified, both Lord and Christ."
			</verse>
			<verse number="37" number-en="37">
				When the people heard this, they were cut to the heart and said to Peter and the other apostles, "Brothers, what shall we do?"
			</verse>
			<verse number="38" number-en="38">
				Peter replied, "Repent and be baptized, every one of you, in the name of Jesus Christ for the forgiveness of your sins. And you will receive the gift of the Holy Spirit.
			</verse>
			<verse number="39" number-en="39">
				The promise is for you and your children and for all who are far off — for all whom the Lord our God will call."
			</verse>
			<verse number="40" number-en="40">
				With many other words he warned them; and he pleaded with them, "Save yourselves from this corrupt generation."
			</verse>
			<verse number="41" number-en="41">
				Those who accepted his message were baptized, and about three thousand were added to their number that day.
			</verse>
			<verse number="42" number-en="42">
				<p class="scripture-heading">
					The Fellowship of the Believers
				</p>
				They devoted themselves to the apostles' teaching and to the fellowship, to the breaking of bread and to prayer.
			</verse>
			<verse number="43" number-en="43">
				Everyone was filled with awe, and many wonders and miraculous signs were done by the apostles.
			</verse>
			<verse number="44" number-en="44">
				All the believers were together and had everything in common.
			</verse>
			<verse number="45" number-en="45">
				Selling their possessions and goods, they gave to anyone as he had need.
			</verse>
			<verse number="46" number-en="46">
				Every day they continued to meet together in the temple courts. They broke bread in their homes and ate together with glad and sincere hearts,
			</verse>
			<verse number="47" number-en="47">
				praising God and enjoying the favor of all the people. And the Lord added to their number daily those who were being saved.
			</verse>
		</chapter>
	</passage>
</scripture>

<!--
			<verse number="" number-en="">
				
			</verse>
			<verse number="" number-en="">
				<p class="scripture-heading">
					Heading text
				</p>
			</verse>
-->
