<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<content key="introduction" lang-original="en" lang-translated="pt" last-updated="2019-02-18" last-updated-by="Waldir Caro" last-updated-by-email="edisone11.fc@gmail.com" created="2018-09-26" created-by="Jason McNeill" created-by-email="vrtjason@gmail.com">
	
	<phrase id="1" desc="title">
		<original>
			Introduction
		</original>
		<translated>
			Introdução
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="2" desc="">
		<original>
			"For when by reason of the time you ought to be teachers, you... need to have someone teach you the rudiments of the first principles of the oracles of God... Therefore leaving the doctrine of the first principles of Christ, let us press on to perfection — not laying again a foundation... of faith toward God, of the teaching of baptisms, of laying on of hands, of resurrection of the dead and of eternal judgment. This will we do!"
		</original>
		<translated>
			De fato, embora a esta altura já devessem ser mestres, vocês precisam de alguém que lhes ensine novamente os princípios elementares da palavra de Deus. Estão precisando de leite, e não de alimento sólido! Quem se alimenta de leite ainda é criança, e não tem experiência no ensino da justiça. Mas o alimento sólido é para os adultos, os quais, pelo exercício constante, tornaram-se aptos para discernir tanto o bem quanto o mal. Portanto, deixemos os ensinos elementares a respeito de Cristo e avancemos para a maturidade, sem lançar novamente o fundamento do arrependimento de atos que conduzem à morte, da fé em Deus, da instrução a respeito de batismos, da imposição de mãos, da ressurreição dos mortos e do juízo eterno. Assim faremos, se Deus o permitir."
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="3" desc="">
		<original>
			Hebrews 5:12; 6:1-3 (WEV)
		</original>
		<translated>
			Hebreus 5:12-14, 6:1-3 (NVI-PT)
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="false">
			<original>
				Hebrews 5:12; 6:1-3
			</original>
			<translated>
				Hebreus 5:12-14, 6:1-3
			</translated>
		</change>
		<change bold="false" italic="true" modal="false">
			<original>
				(WEV)
			</original>
			<translated>
				(NVI-PT)
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="4" desc="">
		<original>
			Originally, the First Principle Studies were written in 1980, while I served the Lord during the formative early days of the Boston Church of Christ. They were revised in 2003 and 2006 to meet the needs and to confront the challenges of the Portland International Church of Christ. In Los Angeles in 2009 and 2012, I made a few more modifications. As of today, these same First Principles Studies are being taught to all the new disciples of the City of Angels International Christian Church. God has greatly blessed these lessons as they have been translated into over 20 languages around the world. May the Lord continue to "solidify, unify and multiply" sold-out disciples everywhere for the evangelization of all the nations in this generation! And to God be the glory! 
		</original>
		<translated>
			Originalmente, os Estudos dos Principios Básicos foram escritos em 1980, enquanto eu servia o Senhor durante os primeiros anos da formação da Igreja de Cristo em Boston. Eles foram revisados em 2003 e 2006 para suprir as necessidades e confrontar os desafios da Igreja de Cristo Internacional de Portland. Em Los Angeles nos anos de 2009 e 2012, eu fiz mais algumas modificações. Nos dias de hoje, estes mesmos Estudos de Principios Básicos estão sendo ensinados à todos os novos discípulos da Igreja Cristã Internacional de Los Angeles. Deus tem abençoado grandemente estas lições ao ponto delas serem traduzidas em mais de 20 idiomas ao redor do mundo. Que o Senhor possa continuar a "solidificar, unificar e multiplicar" discípulos totalmente comprometidos em todos os lugares para a evangelização de todas as nações nesta geração! E que para Deus seja a gloria!
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="false" href="http://www.caicc.net/">
			<original>
				City of Angels International Christian Church
			</original>
			<translated>
				Igreja Cristã Internacional de Los Angeles
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="5" desc="">
		<original>
			Dr. Kip McKean
		</original>
		<translated>
			Dr. Kip McKean
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="6" desc="">
		<original>
			July 1, 2014
		</original>
		<translated>
			1 de Julho de 2014
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<!--
	<phrase id="" desc="">
		<original>
			
		</original>
		<translated>
			
		</translated>
	</phrase>



	<phrase id="" desc="">
		<original>
			
		</original>
		<translated>
			
		</translated>
		<change bold="false" italic="false" modal="false">
			<original>
				
			</original>
			<translated>

			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	-->

</content>
