<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<scripture key="acts-28" lang="en" version="niv" edition="1984">
	<passage title="Acts 28" book="Acts" book-en="Acts">
		<chapter number="28" number-en="28">
			<verse number="1" number-en="1">
				<p class="scripture-heading">
					Ashore on Malta
				</p>
				Once safely on shore, we found out that the island was called Malta.
			</verse>
			<verse number="2" number-en="2">
				The islanders showed us unusual kindness. They built a fire and welcomed us all because it was raining and cold.
			</verse>
			<verse number="3" number-en="3">
				Paul gathered a pile of brushwood and, as he put it on the fire, a viper, driven out by the heat, fastened itself on his hand.
			</verse>
			<verse number="4" number-en="4">
				When the islanders saw the snake hanging from his hand, they said to each other, "This man must be a murderer; for though he escaped from the sea, Justice has not allowed him to live."
			</verse>
			<verse number="5" number-en="5">
				But Paul shook the snake off into the fire and suffered no ill effects.
			</verse>
			<verse number="6" number-en="6">
				The people expected him to swell up or suddenly fall dead, but after waiting a long time and seeing nothing unusual happen to him, they changed their minds and said he was a god.
			</verse>
			<verse number="7" number-en="7">
				There was an estate nearby that belonged to Publius, the chief official of the island. He welcomed us to his home and for three days entertained us hospitably.
			</verse>
			<verse number="8" number-en="8">
				His father was sick in bed, suffering from fever and dysentery. Paul went in to see him and, after prayer, placed his hands on him and healed him.
			</verse>
			<verse number="9" number-en="9">
				When this had happened, the rest of the sick on the island came and were cured.
			</verse>
			<verse number="10" number-en="10">
				They honored us in many ways and when we were ready to sail, they furnished us with the supplies we needed.
			</verse>
			<verse number="11" number-en="11">
				<p class="scripture-heading">
					Arrival at Rome
				</p>
				After three months we put out to sea in a ship that had wintered in the island. It was an Alexandrian ship with the figurehead of the twin gods Castor and Pollux.
			</verse>
			<verse number="12" number-en="12">
				We put in at Syracuse and stayed there three days.
			</verse>
			<verse number="13" number-en="13">
				From there we set sail and arrived at Rhegium. The next day the south wind came up, and on the following day we reached Puteoli.
			</verse>
			<verse number="14" number-en="14">
				There we found some brothers who invited us to spend a week with them. And so we came to Rome.
			</verse>
			<verse number="15" number-en="15">
				The brothers there had heard that we were coming, and they traveled as far as the Forum of Appius and the Three Taverns to meet us. At the sight of these men Paul thanked God and was encouraged.
			</verse>
			<verse number="16" number-en="16">
				When we got to Rome, Paul was allowed to live by himself, with a soldier to guard him.
			</verse>
			<verse number="17" number-en="17">
				<p class="scripture-heading">
					Paul Preaches at Rome Under Guard
				</p>
				Three days later he called together the leaders of the Jews. When they had assembled, Paul said to them, "My brothers, although I have done nothing against our people or against the customs of our ancestors, I was arrested in Jerusalem and handed over to the Romans.
			</verse>
			<verse number="18" number-en="18">
				They examined me and wanted to release me, because I was not guilty of any crime deserving death.
			</verse>
			<verse number="19" number-en="19">
				But when the Jews objected, I was compelled to appeal to Caesar — not that I had any charge to bring against my own people.
			</verse>
			<verse number="20" number-en="20">
				For this reason I have asked to see you and talk with you. It is because of the hope of Israel that I am bound with this chain."
			</verse>
			<verse number="21" number-en="21">
				They replied, "We have not received any letters from Judea concerning you, and none of the brothers who have come from there has reported or said anything bad about you.
			</verse>
			<verse number="22" number-en="22">
				But we want to hear what your views are, for we know that people everywhere are talking against this sect."
			</verse>
			<verse number="23" number-en="23">
				They arranged to meet Paul on a certain day, and came in even larger numbers to the place where he was staying. From morning till evening he explained and declared to them the kingdom of God and tried to convince them about Jesus from the Law of Moses and from the Prophets.
			</verse>
			<verse number="24" number-en="24">
				Some were convinced by what he said, but others would not believe.
			</verse>
			<verse number="25" number-en="25">
				They disagreed among themselves and began to leave after Paul had made this final statement: "The Holy Spirit spoke the truth to your forefathers when he said through Isaiah the prophet:
			</verse>
			<verse number="26" number-en="26" scripturequote="true">
				<span class="scripturequote">'Go to this people and say, "You will be ever hearing but never understanding; you will be ever seeing but never perceiving."</span>
			</verse>
			<verse number="27" number-en="27" scripturequote="true">
				<span class="scripturequote">For this people's heart has become calloused; they hardly hear with their ears, and they have closed their eyes. Otherwise they might see with their eyes, hear with their ears, understand with their hearts and turn, and I would heal them.'</span>
			</verse>
			<verse number="28" number-en="28">
				Therefore I want you to know that God's salvation has been sent to the Gentiles, and they will listen!"
			</verse>
			<verse number="30" number-en="30">
				For two whole years Paul stayed there in his own rented house and welcomed all who came to see him.
			</verse>
			<verse number="31" number-en="31">
				Boldly and without hindrance he preached the kingdom of God and taught about the Lord Jesus Christ.
			</verse>
		</chapter>
	</passage>
</scripture>

<!--
			<verse number="" number-en="">
				
			</verse>
			<verse number="" number-en="">
				<p class="scripture-heading">
					Heading text
				</p>
			</verse>
-->
