<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<scripture key="1-corinthians-14" lang="en" version="niv" edition="1984">
	<passage title="1 Corinthians 14" book="1 Corinthians" book-en="1 Corinthians">
		<chapter number="14" number-en="14">
			<verse number="1" number-en="1">
				<p class="scripture-heading">
					Gifts of Prophecy and Tongues
				</p>
				Follow the way of love and eagerly desire spiritual gifts, especially the gift of prophecy.
			</verse>
			<verse number="2" number-en="2">
				For anyone who speaks in a tongue does not speak to men but to God. Indeed, no one understands him; he utters mysteries with his spirit.
			</verse>
			<verse number="3" number-en="3">
				But everyone who prophesies speaks to men for their strengthening, encouragement and comfort.
			</verse>
			<verse number="4" number-en="4">
				He who speaks in a tongue edifies himself, but he who prophesies edifies the church.
			</verse>
			<verse number="5" number-en="5">
				I would like every one of you to speak in tongues, but I would rather have you prophesy. He who prophesies is greater than one who speaks in tongues, unless he interprets, so that the church may be edified.
			</verse>
			<verse number="6" number-en="6">
				Now, brothers, if I come to you and speak in tongues, what good will I be to you, unless I bring you some revelation or knowledge or prophecy or word of instruction?
			</verse>
			<verse number="7" number-en="7">
				Even in the case of lifeless things that make sounds, such as the flute or harp, how will anyone know what tune is being played unless there is a distinction in the notes?
			</verse>
			<verse number="8" number-en="8">
				Again, if the trumpet does not sound a clear call, who will get ready for battle?
			</verse>
			<verse number="9" number-en="9">
				So it is with you. Unless you speak intelligible words with your tongue, how will anyone know what you are saying? You will just be speaking into the air.
			</verse>
			<verse number="10" number-en="10">
				Undoubtedly there are all sorts of languages in the world, yet none of them is without meaning.
			</verse>
			<verse number="11" number-en="11">
				If then I do not grasp the meaning of what someone is saying, I am a foreigner to the speaker, and he is a foreigner to me.
			</verse>
			<verse number="12" number-en="12">
				So it is with you. Since you are eager to have spiritual gifts, try to excel in gifts that build up the church.
			</verse>
			<verse number="13" number-en="13">
				For this reason anyone who speaks in a tongue should pray that he may interpret what he says.
			</verse>
			<verse number="14" number-en="14">
				For if I pray in a tongue, my spirit prays, but my mind is unfruitful.
			</verse>
			<verse number="15" number-en="15">
				So what shall I do? I will pray with my spirit, but I will also pray with my mind; I will sing with my spirit, but I will also sing with my mind.
			</verse>
			<verse number="16" number-en="16">
				If you are praising God with your spirit, how can one who finds himself among those who do not understand say "Amen" to your thanksgiving, since he does not know what you are saying?
			</verse>
			<verse number="17" number-en="17">
				You may be giving thanks well enough, but the other man is not edified.
			</verse>
			<verse number="18" number-en="18">
				I thank God that I speak in tongues more than all of you.
			</verse>
			<verse number="19" number-en="19">
				But in the church I would rather speak five intelligible words to instruct others than ten thousand words in a tongue.
			</verse>
			<verse number="20" number-en="20">
				Brothers, stop thinking like children. In regard to evil be infants, but in your thinking be adults.
			</verse>
			<verse number="21" number-en="21" scripturequote="true">
				In the Law it is written: <span class="scripturequote">"Through men of strange tongues and through the lips of foreigners I will speak to this people, but even then they will not listen to me," says the Lord.</span>
			</verse>
			<verse number="22" number-en="22">
				Tongues, then, are a sign, not for believers but for unbelievers; prophecy, however, is for believers, not for unbelievers.
			</verse>
			<verse number="23" number-en="23">
				So if the whole church comes together and everyone speaks in tongues, and some who do not understand or some unbelievers come in, will they not say that you are out of your mind?
			</verse>
			<verse number="24" number-en="24">
				But if an unbeliever or someone who does not understand comes in while everybody is prophesying, he will be convinced by all that he is a sinner and will be judged by all,
			</verse>
			<verse number="25" number-en="25">
				and the secrets of his heart will be laid bare. So he will fall down and worship God, exclaiming, "God is really among you!""
			</verse>
			<verse number="26" number-en="26">
				<p class="scripture-heading">
					Orderly Worship
				</p>
				What then shall we say, brothers? When you come together, everyone has a hymn, or a word of instruction, a revelation, a tongue or an interpretation. All of these must be done for the strengthening of the church.
			</verse>
			<verse number="27" number-en="27">
				If anyone speaks in a tongue, two — or at the most three — should speak, one at a time, and someone must interpret.
			</verse>
			<verse number="28" number-en="28">
				If there is no interpreter, the speaker should keep quiet in the church and speak to himself and God.
			</verse>
			<verse number="29" number-en="29">
				Two or three prophets should speak, and the others should weigh carefully what is said.
			</verse>
			<verse number="30" number-en="30">
				And if a revelation comes to someone who is sitting down, the first speaker should stop.
			</verse>
			<verse number="31" number-en="31">
				For you can all prophesy in turn so that everyone may be instructed and encouraged.
			</verse>
			<verse number="32" number-en="32">
				The spirits of prophets are subject to the control of prophets.
			</verse>
			<verse number="33" number-en="33">
				For God is not a God of disorder but of peace. As in all the congregations of the saints,
			</verse>
			<verse number="34" number-en="34">
				women should remain silent in the churches. They are not allowed to speak, but must be in submission, as the Law says.
			</verse>
			<verse number="35" number-en="35">
				If they want to inquire about something, they should ask their own husbands at home; for it is disgraceful for a woman to speak in the church.
			</verse>
			<verse number="36" number-en="36">
				Did the word of God originate with you? Or are you the only people it has reached?
			</verse>
			<verse number="37" number-en="37">
				If anybody thinks he is a prophet or spiritually gifted, let him acknowledge that what I am writing to you is the Lord's command.
			</verse>
			<verse number="38" number-en="38">
				If he ignores this, he himself will be ignored.
			</verse>
			<verse number="39" number-en="39">
				Therefore, my brothers, be eager to prophesy, and do not forbid speaking in tongues.
			</verse>
			<verse number="40" number-en="40">
				But everything should be done in a fitting and orderly way.
			</verse>
		</chapter>
	</passage>
</scripture>

<!--
			<verse number="" number-en="">
				
			</verse>
			<verse number="" number-en="">
				<p class="scripture-heading">
					Heading text
				</p>
			</verse>
-->
