<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<scripture key="acts-22-3-16" lang="en" version="niv" edition="1984">
	<passage title="Acts 22:3-16" book="Acts" book-en="Acts">
		<chapter number="22" number-en="22">
			<verse number="3" number-en="3">
				I am a Jew, born in Tarsus of Cilicia, but brought up in this city. Under Gamaliel I was thoroughly trained in the law of our fathers and was just as zealous for God as any of you are today.
			</verse>
			<verse number="4" number-en="4">
				I persecuted the followers of this Way to their death, arresting both men and women and throwing them into prison,
			</verse>
			<verse number="5" number-en="5">
				as also the high priest and all the Council can testify. I even obtained letters from them to their brothers in Damascus, and went there to bring these people as prisoners to Jerusalem to be punished.
			</verse>
			<verse number="6" number-en="6">
				About noon as I came near Damascus, suddenly a bright light from heaven flashed around me.
			</verse>
			<verse number="7" number-en="7" jesuswords="true">
				I fell to the ground and heard a voice say to me, "<span class="jesuswords">Saul! Saul! Why do you persecute me?</span>"
			</verse>
			<verse number="8" number-en="8" jesuswords="true">
				"Who are you, Lord?" I asked. "<span class="jesuswords">I am Jesus of Nazareth, whom you are persecuting,</span>" he replied.
			</verse>
			<verse number="9" number-en="9">
				My companions saw the light, but they did not understand the voice of him who was speaking to me.
			</verse>
			<verse number="10" number-en="10" jesuswords="true">
				"What shall I do, Lord?" I asked. "<span class="jesuswords">Get up,</span>" the Lord said, "<span class="jesuswords">and go into Damascus. There you will be told all that you have been assigned to do.</span>"
			</verse>
			<verse number="11" number-en="11">
				My companions led me by the hand into Damascus, because the brilliance of the light had blinded me.
			</verse>
			<verse number="12" number-en="12">
				A man named Ananias came to see me. He was a devout observer of the law and highly respected by all the Jews living there.
			</verse>
			<verse number="13" number-en="13">
				He stood beside me and said, "Brother Saul, receive your sight!" And at that very moment I was able to see him.
			</verse>
			<verse number="14" number-en="14">
				Then he said: "The God of our fathers has chosen you to know his will and to see the Righteous One and to hear words from his mouth.
			</verse>
			<verse number="15" number-en="15">
				You will be his witness to all men of what you have seen and heard.
			</verse>
			<verse number="16" number-en="16">
				And now what are you waiting for? Get up, be baptized and wash your sins away, calling on his name."
			</verse>
		</chapter>
	</passage>
</scripture>

<!--
			<verse number="" number-en="">
				
			</verse>
			<verse number="" number-en="">
				<p class="scripture-heading">
					Heading text
				</p>
			</verse>
-->
