<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<scripture key="colossians-3-15-24" lang="en" version="niv" edition="1984">
	<passage title="Colossians 3:15-24" book="Colossians" book-en="Colossians">
		<chapter number="3" number-en="3">
			<verse number="15" number-en="15">
				Let the peace of Christ rule in your hearts, since as members of one body you were called to peace. And be thankful.
			</verse>
			<verse number="16" number-en="16">
				Let the word of Christ dwell in you richly as you teach and admonish one another with all wisdom, and as you sing psalms, hymns and spiritual songs with gratitude in your hearts to God.
			</verse>
			<verse number="17" number-en="17">
				And whatever you do, whether in word or deed, do it all in the name of the Lord Jesus, giving thanks to God the Father through him.
			</verse>
			<verse number="18" number-en="18">
				Wives, submit to your husbands, as is fitting in the Lord.
			</verse>
			<verse number="19" number-en="19">
				Husbands, love your wives and do not be harsh with them.
			</verse>
			<verse number="20" number-en="20">
				Children, obey your parents in everything, for this pleases the Lord.
			</verse>
			<verse number="21" number-en="21">
				Fathers, do not embitter your children, or they will become discouraged.
			</verse>
			<verse number="22" number-en="22">
				Slaves, obey your earthly masters in everything; and do it, not only when their eye is on you and to win their favor, but with sincerity of heart and reverence for the Lord.
			</verse>
			<verse number="23" number-en="23">
				Whatever you do, work at it with all your heart, as working for the Lord, not for men,
			</verse>
			<verse number="24" number-en="24">
				since you know that you will receive an inheritance from the Lord as a reward. It is the Lord Christ you are serving.
			</verse>
		</chapter>
	</passage>
</scripture>

<!--
			<verse number="" number-en="">
				
			</verse>
			<verse number="" number-en="">
				<p class="scripture-heading">
					Heading text
				</p>
			</verse>
-->
