<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<content key="introduction" lang-original="en" lang-translated="zh" last-updated="2020-02-03" last-updated-by="Dean Lam" last-updated-by-email="Dean-lin_zh@Hotmail.com" created="2018-09-26" created-by="Jason McNeill" created-by-email="vrtjason@gmail.com">
	
	<phrase id="1" desc="title">
		<original>
			Introduction
		</original>
		<translated>
			序
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="2" desc="">
		<original>
			"For when by reason of the time you ought to be teachers, you... need to have someone teach you the rudiments of the first principles of the oracles of God... Therefore leaving the doctrine of the first principles of Christ, let us press on to perfection — not laying again a foundation... of faith toward God, of the teaching of baptisms, of laying on of hands, of resurrection of the dead and of eternal judgment. This will we do!"
		</original>
		<translated>
			“到这个时候，你们应该已经作老师了；可是你们还需要有人再把　神道理的初步教导你们。你们成了只能吃奶而不能吃乾粮的人……所以，我们应当离开基督初步的道理，努力进到成熟的地步，不必在懊悔致死的行为，信靠　神，洗礼，按手礼，死人复活，和永远审判的教训上再立根基。只要　神允许，我们就这样作！”
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="3" desc="">
		<original>
			Hebrews 5:12; 6:1-3 (WEV)
		</original>
		<translated>
			希伯来书 5:12; 6:1-3 (CNVS)
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="false">
			<original>
				Hebrews 5:12; 6:1-3
			</original>
			<translated>
				希伯来书 5:12; 6:1-3 (CNVS)
			</translated>
		</change>
		<change bold="false" italic="true" modal="false">
			<original>
				(WEV)
			</original>
			<translated>
				(CNVS)
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="4" desc="">
		<original>
			Originally, the First Principle Studies were written in 1980, while I served the Lord during the formative early days of the Boston Church of Christ. They were revised in 2003 and 2006 to meet the needs and to confront the challenges of the Portland International Church of Christ. In Los Angeles in 2009 and 2012, I made a few more modifications. As of today, these same First Principles Studies are being taught to all the new disciples of the City of Angels International Christian Church. God has greatly blessed these lessons as they have been translated into over 20 languages around the world. May the Lord continue to "solidify, unify and multiply" sold-out disciples everywhere for the evangelization of all the nations in this generation! And to God be the glory! 
		</original>
		<translated>
			《首要原则》圣经学习课程最初写于1980年，当时我在主內服事成立不久的Boston Church of Christ（波士顿旧国际基督教会），在2003年和2006年修订，以协助和处理当时Portland International Christian Church（波特兰国际基督教会）面临的挑战。其后的2009年和2012年，我在洛杉矶时也做过几次修改。这就是一直到今天仍被教给City of Angels International Christian Church（天使之城国际基督教会）里所有新门徒的《首要原则》。
神已大大地祝福了这些课程，到今为止，《首要原则》已在世界各地被翻译成了20多种语言。愿主继续在万国遍地「固化、倍化、统一化」全心委身的门徒，以将福音在这个世代传遍地极！荣耀归于上帝！

		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="false" href="http://www.caicc.net/">
			<original>
				City of Angels International Christian Church
			</original>
			<translated>
				天使之城国际基督教会
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="5" desc="">
		<original>
			Dr. Kip McKean
		</original>
		<translated>
			基普·麦基恩　博士 
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="6" desc="">
		<original>
			July 1, 2014
		</original>
		<translated>
			写于2014年7月1日
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<!--
	<phrase id="" desc="">
		<original>
			
		</original>
		<translated>
			
		</translated>
	</phrase>



	<phrase id="" desc="">
		<original>
			
		</original>
		<translated>
			
		</translated>
		<change bold="false" italic="false" modal="false">
			<original>
				
			</original>
			<translated>
				
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	-->

</content>
