<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<content key="the-church" lang-original="en" lang-translated="pt" last-updated="2019-02-18" last-updated-by="Waldir Caro" last-updated-by-email="edisone11.fc@gmail.com" created="2018-09-29" created-by="Jason McNeill" created-by-email="vrtjason@gmail.com">
	
	<phrase id="1" desc="title">
		<original>
			The Church
		</original>
		<translated>
			A Igreja
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="2" desc="">
		<original>
			Colossians 1:15-18
		</original>
		<translated>
			Colossenses 1:15-18
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="true" scripturekey="colossians-1-15-18">
			<original>
				Colossians 1:15-18
			</original>
			<translated>
				Colossenses 1:15-18
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="3" desc="">
		<original>
			The church is the body of Christ. The body needs the head. The church is essential to Christianity.
		</original>
		<translated>
			A igreja é o corpo de Cristo. O corpo precisa da cabeça. A igreja é essencial para o cristianismo.
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="4" desc="">
		<original>
			HEAD
		</original>
		<translated>
			CABEÇA
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="5" desc="">
		<original>
			CHRIST
		</original>
		<translated>
			CRISTO
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="6" desc="">
		<original>
			BODY
		</original>
		<translated>
			CORPO
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="7" desc="">
		<original>
			CHURCH
		</original>
		<translated>
			IGREJA
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="8" desc="">
		<original>
			Ephesians 2:19-21
		</original>
		<translated>
			Efésios 2:19-21
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="true" scripturekey="ephesians-2-19-21">
			<original>
				Ephesians 2:19-21
			</original>
			<translated>
				Efésios 2:19-21
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="9" desc="">
		<original>
			The church is the family of God.
		</original>
		<translated>
			A igreja é a família de Deus
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="10" desc="">
		<original>
			GOD
		</original>
		<translated>
			DEUS
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="11" desc="">
		<original>
			(Father)
		</original>
		<translated>
			(Pai)
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="12" desc="">
		<original>
			Christian
		</original>
		<translated>
			Cristão
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="13" desc="">
		<original>
			(Son)
		</original>
		<translated>
			(Filho)
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="14" desc="">
		<original>
			Brothers
		</original>
		<translated>
			Irmãos
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="15" desc="">
		<original>
			Christian
		</original>
		<translated>
			Cristão
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="16" desc="">
		<original>
			(Son)
		</original>
		<translated>
			(Filho)
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="17" desc="">
		<original>
			1 Corinthians 12:12-13 teaches that we are baptized into the body of Christ, the church.
		</original>
		<translated>
			1 Coríntios 12:12-13 Batizados no corpo de Cristo – a Igreja.
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="true" scripturekey="1-corinthians-12-12-13">
			<original>
				1 Corinthians 12:12-13
			</original>
			<translated>
				1 Coríntios 12:12-13
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="18" desc="">
		<original>
			Romans 6:3-4 teaches that we are also baptized into Christ. Baptism is when we become Christian, a son of God, and at that same point we become members of the church, the family of God.
		</original>
		<translated>
			Romanos 6:3-4: Ensina que também somos batizados em Cristo. É no batismo que nos tornamos cristãos, filhos de Deus, e nesse mesmo momento,nos tornamos membros da igreja, a família de Deus.
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="true" scripturekey="romans-6-3-4">
			<original>
				Romans 6:3-4
			</original>
			<translated>
				Romanos 6:3-4
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="19" desc="">
		<original>
			Ephesians 2:20
		</original>
		<translated>
			Efésios 2:20
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="true" scripturekey="ephesians-2-20">
			<original>
				Ephesians 2:20
			</original>
			<translated>
				Efésios 2:20
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="20" desc="">
		<original>
			Cornerstone: Christ
		</original>
		<translated>
			Pedra angular: Cristo.
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="21" desc="">
		<original>
			Foundation: Apostles and Prophets
		</original>
		<translated>
			Fundação: Apóstolos e profetas
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="22" desc="">
		<original>
			Apostles = New Testament Bible
		</original>
		<translated>
			Apóstolos = Novo Testamento da Bíblia
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="23" desc="">
		<original>
			Prophets = Old Testament
		</original>
		<translated>
			Profetas = Antigo Testamento
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="24" desc="">
		<original>
			The church is based on the Word of God only.
		</original>
		<translated>
			A igreja é baseada apenas na Palavra de Deus.
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="25" desc="">
		<original>
			Have you ever wondered why there are so many denominations — divisions? (450 or more exist in the U.S. alone.)
		</original>
		<translated>
			Você já se perguntou por que há tantas denominações - divisões? (existem mais de 500, só no Brasil)
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="false">
			<original>
				Have you ever wondered why there are so many denominations — divisions?
			</original>
			<translated>
				Você já se perguntou por que há tantas denominações - divisões?
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="26" desc="">
		<original>
			The Bible teaches that there is one church.
		</original>
		<translated>
			A Bíblia ensina que há uma só igreja
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="27" desc="">
		<original>
			Ephesians 4:4-6 — one body
		</original>
		<translated>
			Efésios 4:4-6 - Um corpo
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="true" scripturekey="ephesians-4-4-6">
			<original>
				Ephesians 4:4-6
			</original>
			<translated>
				Efésios 4:4-6
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="28" desc="">
		<original>
			Romans 12:4-5 — one body
		</original>
		<translated>
			Romanos 12:4-5 - Um corpo
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="true" scripturekey="romans-12-4-5">
			<original>
				Romans 12:4-5
			</original>
			<translated>
				Romanos 12:4-5
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="29" desc="">
		<original>
			1 Corinthians 12:12-13 — one body
		</original>
		<translated>
			1 Coríntios 12:12-13 - Um corpo
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="true" scripturekey="1-corinthians-12-12-13">
			<original>
				1 Corinthians 12:12-13
			</original>
			<translated>
				1 Coríntios 12:12-13
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="30" desc="">
		<original>
			Divisions in Christendom are either of Satan or of God.
		</original>
		<translated>
			Divisões da cristandade são ou de Satanás ou de Deus.
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="31" desc="">
		<original>
			1 Corinthians 1:10-13: Division is sin, when following personalities and in time their writings (traditions of men that contradict the Word — false doctrines). Matthew 15:6-9
		</original>
		<translated>
			1 Coríntios 1:10-13: Divisão é pecado, quando se segue personalidades e com o tempo, seus escritos. (Tradição dos homens que contradizem a Palavra - falsas doutrinas) Mateus 15:6-9
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="true" scripturekey="1-corinthians-1-10-13">
			<original>
				1 Corinthians 1:10-13
			</original>
			<translated>
				1 Coríntios 1:10-13
			</translated>
		</change>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="true" scripturekey="matthew-15-6-9">
			<original>
				Matthew 15:6-9
			</original>
			<translated>
				Mateus 15:6-9
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="32" desc="">
		<original>
			Luke 12:51-53; John 10:19-21: Division will occur and is righteous, when an individual, church or movement aligns themselves with the Word of God. The Jews considered themselves "God's people," yet Jesus' words (the truth) divided them into two groups — those who opposed Him and those who obeyed Him.
		</original>
		<translated>
			Lucas 12:51-53; João 10:19-21: Divisão ocorrerá e é justa quando um indivíduo, movimento ou igreja se alinha com a Palavra de Deus. Os judeus consideravam-se o "povo de Deus", mas as palavras de Jesus (a Verdade) os dividiram em dois grupos: aqueles que se opuseram a Ele e aqueles que O obedeceram.
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="true" scripturekey="luke-12-51-53">
			<original>
				Luke 12:51-53
			</original>
			<translated>
				Lucas 12:51-53
			</translated>
		</change>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="true" scripturekey="john-10-19-21">
			<original>
				John 10:19-21
			</original>
			<translated>
				João 10:19-21
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="33" desc="">
		<original>
			The following are the major historical divisions in Christendom — some were formed by a noble stand for the truth (though not a complete return), while others were departures from the truth.
		</original>
		<translated>
			Estas são as principais divisões da cristandade - Algumas foram formadas por uma causa nobre para a verdade (embora não um retorno completo) enquanto outras se distanciaram da verdade.
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="34" desc="">
		<original>
			Through the centuries the church was corrupted by traditions of men — false doctrines, such as: infant baptism, original sin, perpetual virginity of Mary, priests as clergy, papal infallibility, etc… This becomes the Catholic Church. In 364 AD the Roman Empire is split into two parts. This division leads to a split in Christianity — the eastern portion becomes the Eastern Orthodox Church and the western part becomes the Roman Catholic Church. Practices diverge, for example — Orthodox has married priests, Roman Catholic priests are celibate. The "Great Schism" occurs in 1054 AD, as the leaders of "each church" excommunicate each other.
		</original>
		<translated>
			 Através dos séculos, a igreja foi corrompida pelas tradições dos homens - as falsas doutrinas, tais como: batismo infantil, pecado original, a virgindade perpétua de Maria, sacerdotes como clérigo, infalibilidade papal, etc. Isto se tornou a Igreja Católica. Em 364 d.C. o Império Romano se divide em duas partes. Essa separação leva a uma divisão na cristandade – a parte oriental se torna a Igreja Ortodoxa Oriental e a parte ocidental se torna a Igreja Católica Romana. Práticas divergem: por exemplo - Ortodoxa tem padres casados, sacerdotes católicos são celibatários. O "Grande Cisma" ocorre em 1054 d.C. quando os líderes de "cada igreja" se excomungam mutuamente.
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="false">
			<original>
				Catholic Church
			</original>
			<translated>
				Igreja Católica
			</translated>
		</change>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="false">
			<original>
				Eastern Orthodox Church
			</original>
			<translated>
				Igreja Ortodoxa Oriental
			</translated>
		</change>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="false">
			<original>
				Roman Catholic Church
			</original>
			<translated>
				Igreja Católica Romana
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="35" desc="">
		<original>
			1500's Reformation Movement — Martin Luther (Lutheran Church) He takes a stand against the Roman Catholic Church on these convictions: Bible authority over church authority, salvation by faith not works, and the priesthood of all believers, yet still baptizes infants. Other noted reformers were John Calvin (Presbyterian Church), Ulrich Zwingli and Conrad Grebel (Anabaptists). Anabaptists were heavily persecuted by Catholics and some reformers, because of their stand for adult baptism. Henry VIII (Anglican Church / Church of England) He breaks from the Catholic Church over his right to divorce his wife. He appoints himself head of the church. Later in the United States, the Anglican Church becomes the Episcopalian Church, since members will not follow the king of England.
		</original>
		<translated>
			Movimento da Reforma em 1500 - Martinho Lutero (Igreja Luterana) toma uma posição contra a Igreja Católica Romana sobre essas convicções: Autoridade da bíblia sobre a autoridade da igreja, a salvação pela fé e não por obras, e o sacerdócio de todos os crentes; ainda assim, mantém o batismo infantil. Outros reformadores notáveis foram: João Calvino (Igreja Presbiteriana), Ulrich Zwingli e Conrado Grebel (Anabatistas). Os anabatistas foram fortemente perseguidos por católicos e por alguns reformistas, por causa de sua posição de batismo para adultos. Henrique VIII (Igreja Anglicana/Igreja da Inglaterra) se separa da Igreja Católica, pelo direito de se divorciar de sua esposa. Ele se nomeia chefe da igreja. Mais tarde, nos Estados Unidos, a Igreja Anglicana se torna a igreja Episcopal, já que os membros não seguiriam o Rei da Inglaterra.
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="false">
			<original>
				1500's Reformation Movement
			</original>
			<translated>
				Movimento da Reforma em 1500
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="36" desc="">
		<original>
			1700's Great Awakening Movement — John and Charles Wesley (Methodist Church). Followers divide from Church of England over: personal transforming decision for Christ not state religion, high accountability of members, and preaching to the "unchurched;" also practiced infant baptism.
		</original>
		<translated>
			Movimento de 1700, O Grande Despertar - João e Charles Wesley (Igreja Metodista). Seguidores se dividem da igreja por: decisão de transformação pessoal por Cristo e não religião estatal, cobrança elevada aos membros, e pregando para os "sem igreja"; batismo infantil também é praticado.
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="false">
			<original>
				1700's Great Awakening Movement
			</original>
			<translated>
				Movimento de 1700, O Grande Despertar
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="37" desc="">
		<original>
			1800's Restoration Movement — Alexander Campbell and Barton Stone (Mainline Church of Christ and Conservative Christian Church) Take a stand against both Catholic and Protestant doctrines of salvation. They preach to be saved one must have personal faith in Christ, repentance and baptism (immersion) for the forgiveness of sin to receive the Holy Spirit. In reaction to Catholicism, their congregations are autonomous — self-governing. (1906 is the formal split between Mainline Church of Christ, which is non-instrumental, and the Conservative Christian Church, which is instrumental.) Joseph Smith (Mormon Church) divides from Restoration Movement in 1830 over "new revelation" — the Book of Mormon.
		</original>
		<translated>
			Movimento de Restauração de 1800 - Alexandre Campbell e Barton Stone (Igreja Tradicional de Cristo e da Igreja Cristã Conservadora) tomaram uma posição contra as doutrinas tanto católicas quanto protestantes da salvação. Eles pregaram que para ser salvo, é preciso ter fé pessoal em Cristo, o arrependimento e o batismo (imersão) para o perdão dos pecados e receber o Espírito Santo. Em reação ao catolicismo, suas congregações são autônomas - autogovernadas. (em 1906, acontece a separação formal da Igreja Tradicional de Cristo, que é não-instrumental, e a igreja cristã conservadora, que é instrumental). Joseph Smith (Igreja Mórmon) se separa do movimento de restauração em 1830, a partir de uma "nova revelação" - o Livro de Mórmon.
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="false">
			<original>
				1800's Restoration Movement
			</original>
			<translated>
				Movimento de Restauração de 1800
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="38" desc="">
		<original>
			1967 Crossroads Movement (Total Commitment Movement) — Controversial, though never departing from the Mainline Church of Christ, the Crossroads Church near the University of Florida pioneers evangelizing the secular campuses of United States, "counting the cost" with each person that desires to be baptized, and the shepherding of new converts.
		</original>
		<translated>
			1967 – Movimento Crossroads (Movimento do Comprometimento Total) Controversa, apesar de nunca terem partido da Igreja Tradicional de Cristo, a Igreja Crossroads perto da Universidade da Flórida, é pioneira em evangelizar os campus seculares dos Estados Unidos, "calculando o custo" com cada pessoa que deseja ser batizada, e cuidando dos novos convertidos.
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="false">
			<original>
				1967 Crossroads Movement
			</original>
			<translated>
				1967 – Movimento Crossroads
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="39" desc="">
		<original>
			1979 Boston Movement (International Church of Christ) — Kip McKean — Baptized at the University of Florida in 1972, divides from Mainline Churches of Christ and Crossroads Movement over: Bible Church not just New Testament Church, only disciples are true Christians, each and every member of church must be a disciple, each member should be in discipling relationships, vision to evangelize the nations in a generation, the planting of new churches to achieve this vision, central leadership not autonomous congregations, and the role of women. In 2002, the International Churches of Christ return to a more Mainline Church of Christ theology — each congregation becomes autonomous (self-governing), calling a central leadership and the vision to evangelize the nations in a generation "unbiblical." Around the world, thousands fall away.
		</original>
		<translated>
			1979 – Movimento de Boston (Igreja Internacional de Cristo) - Kip Mckean - batizado na Universidade da Flórida em 1972, divide a Igreja Tradicional de Cristo e o Movimento da Encruzilhada em: Igreja da Bíblia, não apenas Igreja do Novo Testamento, apenas discípulos são verdadeiros cristãos; todo e cada membro da igreja deve ser um discípulo, cada membro deve estar em relacionamentos de discipulado, ter visão de evangelizar as nações em uma geração, plantar novas igrejas para alcançar essa visão, uma liderança central e não congregações autônomas, bem como o papel das mulheres. Em 2002 as Igrejas Internacionais de Cristo voltam a ser teologicamente mais como as Igrejas Tradicionais de Cristo - cada congregação torna-se autônoma (auto-gestão), chamando a liderança central e a visão de evangelizar as nações em uma geração "anti-bíblica". Em todo o mundo, milhares caíram.
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="false">
			<original>
				1979 Boston Movement
			</original>
			<translated>
				1979 – Movimento de Boston
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="40" desc="">
		<original>
			2006 SoldOut Movement (Portland Movement / International Christian Church): Begins in Portland, Oregon as a revival movement within the International Churches of Christ. The International Church of Christ separates from the SoldOut Movement, because of the new movement's stand on these convictions: Bible Church not just New Testament Church, only disciples are true Christians, each and every member of church must be a disciple, each member should be in discipling relationships, vision to evangelize the nations in a generation, the planting of new churches to achieve this vision, central leadership not autonomous congregations, and the role of women.
		</original>
		<translated>
			2006 – Movimento do Compromisso Total (SoldOut) (Movimento de Portland/Igreja Cristã Internacional) começa em Portland, Oregon como um movimento de renovação dentro da Igreja Internacional de Cristo. A Igreja Internacional de Cristo se separa do Movimento de Comprometimento Total, porque o novo movimento apoia estas convicções: Igreja da Bíblia não só Igreja do Novo Testamento, apenas os discípulos são verdadeiros cristãos; todo e cada membro da igreja deve ser um discípulo, cada membro deve estar em um relacionamento de discipulado, a visão de evangelizar as nações em uma geração, o plantio de novas igrejas para alcançar essa visão, liderança central e não congregações autônomas, bem como o papel das mulheres.
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="false">
			<original>
				2006 SoldOut Movement
			</original>
			<translated>
				2006 – Movimento do Compromisso Total (SoldOut)
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="41" desc="">
		<original>
			What is the "one church?"
		</original>
		<translated>
			Qual é a "única igreja"?
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="42" desc="">
		<original>
			Acts 11:25-26: Church = Disciples = Christians. When God looks down from heaven, He sees one church — all the baptized disciples around the world, who are "sold-out" in obeying his Word. This is called the "church universal" — the one true church (Ephesians 4:4-6).
		</original>
		<translated>
			Atos 11:25-26: Igreja = Discípulos = Cristãos. Quando Deus olha do céu para baixo, Ele vê uma igreja - todos os discípulos batizados em todo o mundo, que estão "comprometidos" na obediência à Sua palavra. Essa é a chamada a única igreja verdadeira. (Efésios 4:4-8)
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="true" scripturekey="acts-11-25-26">
			<original>
				Acts 11:25-26
			</original>
			<translated>
				Atos 11:25-26
			</translated>
		</change>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="false">
			<original>
				Church = Disciples = Christians.
			</original>
			<translated>
				Igreja = Discípulos = Cristãos
			</translated>
		</change>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="true" scripturekey="ephesians-4-4-6">
			<original>
				Ephesians 4:4-6
			</original>
			<translated>
				Efésios 4:4-8
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="43" desc="">
		<original>
			A local congregation is called the "visible church." In the first century, all the "visible churches" made up the "church universal." However, since so many "visible churches" have departed from true doctrine and because all sold-out baptized disciples are not in one fellowship, we should strive to be a member of a local congregation.
		</original>
		<translated>
			Uma congregação local é chamada de "igreja visível". No primeiro século, todas as "igrejas visíveis" compunham a "igreja verdadeira" No entanto, como tantas "igrejas visíveis" se afastaram da verdadeira doutrina e porque todos os discípulos batizados e comprometidos não estão em uma congregação, devemos nos esforçar para ser um membro de uma congregação local.
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="44" desc="">
		<original>
			The Greek word for church is "ekklesia" which means "assembly" or "called out" ("Ek" meaning "out" and "kaleo" meaning "to call"). To be a disciple is to be "called out" from the world. Therefore, the church in the Bible was the "assembly" of the "called out."
		</original>
		<translated>
			A palavra grega para igreja é "ekklesia", que significa "assembleia" ou "chamado". ("Ek" significa "fora" e "kaleo", que significa "chamar".) Ser discípulo é ser "chamado para fora" do mundo. Portanto, a igreja na Bíblia era a "assembleia" dos "chamados".
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="45" desc="">
		<original>
			There are several names in the Bible for God's Church: Disciples, Christians, Church of God, Church of Christ, The Way, Church of the Firstborn, Saints, etc... Since we are free to choose any name for our fellowship, since our fellowship goes around the world, and because our churches are composed of only sold-out disciples, we call ourselves the "International Christian Church."
		</original>
		<translated>
			Existe vários nomes na Bíblia para a Igreja de Deus: Discípulos, Cristãos, Igreja de Deus, Igreja de Cristo, O Caminho, Igreja do Primogênito, Santos, etc. Uma vez que somos livres para escolher qualquer nome para a nossa congregação, desde que ela percorra todo o mundo, e porque as nossas igrejas são compostas de apenas discípulos comprometidos, nós nos denominamos "Igreja Cristã Internacional."
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="46" desc="">
		<original>
			What distinguishes the International Christian Churches? (What separates or "divides" us from mainstream Christendom?)
		</original>
		<translated>
			O que distingue as Igrejas Cristãs Internacionais? (O que nos separa ou "divide" do fluxo principal da Cristandade)
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="47" desc="">
		<original>
			We believe God physically resurrected Jesus from the dead.
		</original>
		<translated>
			Acreditamos que Deus ressuscitou Jesus fisicamente dentre os mortos.
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="48" desc="">
		<original>
			We believe the Bible is inspired by God and is our sole authority. Therefore, since we have not departed (divided) from the truth, we consider ourselves non-denominational.
		</original>
		<translated>
			Cremos que a Bíblia é inspirada por Deus e é nossa única autoridade. Portanto, uma vez que não nos afastamos (dividimos) da verdade, nos consideramos sem denominação.
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="false">
			<original>
				We believe the Bible is inspired by God and is our sole authority.
			</original>
			<translated>
				Cremos que a Bíblia é inspirada por Deus e é nossa única autoridade.
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="49" desc="">
		<original>
			We are a Bible Church, not simply a New Testament Church. 2 Timothy 3:14-17. The context of the word "Scripture" is referring to the Old Testament. We believe the Old Testament applies to our lives — as much as the New Testament — except for the Mosaic Law and any teaching in the New Testament that supercedes the Old Testament (Example: grounds for divorce).
		</original>
		<translated>
			Somos uma Igreja da Bíblia, não simplesmente uma Igreja do Novo Testamento: 2 Timóteo 3:14-17. O contexto da palavra "Escritura" está se referindo ao Antigo Testamento. Acreditamos que o Antigo Testamento se aplique às nossas vidas - tanto quanto o Novo Testamento - exceto a Lei de Moisés e qualquer ensinamento no Novo Testamento que substitua o Antigo Testamento (Exemplo: Motivos para o divórcio)
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="false">
			<original>
				We are a Bible Church, not simply a New Testament Church.
			</original>
			<translated>
				Somos uma Igreja da Bíblia, não simplesmente uma Igreja do Novo Testamento
			</translated>
		</change>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="true" scripturekey="2-timothy-3-14-17">
			<original>
				2 Timothy 3:14-17
			</original>
			<translated>
				2 Timóteo 3:14-17
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="50" desc="">
		<original>
			We believe — as in the book of Acts — the visible church should be composed of only sold-out baptized disciples.
		</original>
		<translated>
			Acreditamos - como no livro de Atos – que a igreja visível deve ser composta por discípulos batizados comprometidos.
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="51" desc="">
		<original>
			"Be silent where the Bible speaks, and speak where the Bible is silent." In applying Scriptural principles to build the visible church, we believe we must obey God's Word, but where the Bible does not prohibit a practice or name, we are free to use our God-given creativity. Genesis 2:19 (Examples: The principles for "Bible Talks," "Lead Evangelist," "Discipleship Partners" and "Regions" are in the Scriptures, though these terms are not. However, nowhere are they prohibited. Also instrumental music and paid Women's Ministry Leaders are not prohibited in the Scriptures.)
		</original>
		<translated>
			"Fique em silêncio onde a Bíblia fala e fale onde a Bíblia é silenciosa". Na aplicação dos princípios bíblicos para construir a igreja visível, acreditamos que devemos obedecer a Palavra de Deus, mas onde a Bíblia não proíbe a prática ou o nome, estamos livres para usar nossa criatividade dada por Deus. Gênesis 2:19 (Exemplos: Os princípios de "Bate-papos", "Evangelista principal", "Discipulado em Parceria" e "Setores" estão nas Escrituras, embora estes termos não. No entanto, em nenhum lugar eles são proibidos. Também, música instrumental e mulheres remuneradas como líderes do ministério não são proibidas nas Escrituras).
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="false">
			<original>
				"Be silent where the Bible speaks, and speak where the Bible is silent."
			</original>
			<translated>
				"Fique em silêncio onde a Bíblia fala e fale onde a Bíblia é silenciosa".
			</translated>
		</change>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="true" scripturekey="genesis-2-19">
			<original>
				Genesis 2:19
			</original>
			<translated>
				Gênesis 2:19
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="52" desc="">
		<original>
			We believe in a Central Leadership. Throughout God's Word, when His people were unified, there was a strong central leadership and godly central leader. (Examples: Moses, Joshua, David and of course Jesus and the Apostles.) 1 Corinthians 4:15-17 and Titus 1:5 teaches that local congregations had an overseeing evangelist, who unified the disciples "everywhere in every church." In the first century, congregations were a collective movement — not autonomous, not self-governing.)
		</original>
		<translated>
			Nós acreditamos em uma liderança central. Ao longo da Palavra de Deus, quando o Seu povo foi unificado, houve uma forte liderança central e líder central piedoso. (Exemplos: Moisés, Josué, David e, claro, Jesus e os Apóstolos) 1 Coríntios 4:15-17 e Tito 1:5 ensinam que as congregações locais tinham um evangelista supervisionando, que unificou os discípulos "em todos os lugares, em todas as igrejas". No primeiro século, as congregações eram um movimento coletivo – não autônomo, não autogovernadas)
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="false">
			<original>
				We believe in a Central Leadership.
			</original>
			<translated>
				Nós acreditamos em uma liderança central.
			</translated>
		</change>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="true" scripturekey="1-corinthians-4-15-17">
			<original>
				1 Corinthians 4:15-17
			</original>
			<translated>
				1 Coríntios 4:15-17
			</translated>
		</change>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="true" scripturekey="titus-1-5">
			<original>
				Titus 1:5
			</original>
			<translated>
				Tito 1:5
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="53" desc="">
		<original>
			Matthew 28:19-20: Our vision — the evangelization of all nations in this generation — will be accomplished through every disciple making disciples and every disciple having discipling relationships.
		</original>
		<translated>
			Mateus 28:19-20: Nossa visão - A evangelização de todas as nações nesta geração - será alcançada através de cada discípulo fazendo discípulos, e cada discípulo tendo relacionamentos de discipulado.
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="true" scripturekey="matthew-28-19-20">
			<original>
				Matthew 28:19-20
			</original>
			<translated>
				Mateus 28:19-20
			</translated>
		</change>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="false">
			<original>
				Our vision — the evangelization of all nations in this generation — 
			</original>
			<translated>
				Nossa visão - A evangelização de todas as nações nesta geração
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="54" desc="">
		<original>
			1 Corinthians 12:14-27
		</original>
		<translated>
			1 Coríntios 12:14-27
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="true" scripturekey="1-corinthians-12-14-27">
			<original>
				1 Corinthians 12:14-27
			</original>
			<translated>
				1 Coríntios 12:14-27
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="55" desc="">
		<original>
			We need the body. The body needs us (v. 21).
		</original>
		<translated>
			Nós precisamos do corpo. O corpo precisa de nós. (v. 21)
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="true" scripturekey="1-corinthians-12-21">
			<original>
				v. 21
			</original>
			<translated>
				v. 21
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="56" desc="">
		<original>
			Be involved on a relationship level in the church (v. 26).
		</original>
		<translated>
			Estar envolvido em um nível de relacionamento na igreja (v. 26)
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="true" scripturekey="1-corinthians-12-26">
			<original>
				v. 26
			</original>
			<translated>
				v. 26
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="57" desc="">
		<original>
			Hebrews 10:23-25
		</original>
		<translated>
			Hebreus 10:23-25
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="true" scripturekey="hebrews-10-23-25">
			<original>
				Hebrews 10:23-25
			</original>
			<translated>
				Hebreus 10:23-25
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="58" desc="">
		<original>
			Do not miss church.
		</original>
		<translated>
			Não falte aos cultos
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="59" desc="">
		<original>
			The fellowship helps us to be unswerving in our commitment (v. 23).
		</original>
		<translated>
			A congregação nos ajuda a ficar firmes em nosso compromisso (v.23)
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="true" scripturekey="hebrews-10-23">
			<original>
				v. 23
			</original>
			<translated>
				v. 23
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="60" desc="">
		<original>
			Another purpose of fellowship is to encourage each other so we will remain faithful (v. 24).
		</original>
		<translated>
			Outra finalidade de congregar é encorajar uns aos outros para permanecermos fiéis (v. 24).
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="true" scripturekey="hebrews-10-24">
			<original>
				v. 24
			</original>
			<translated>
				v. 24
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="61" desc="">
		<original>
			Must come to all meetings of the body: Sunday and Midweek Services, Bible Talks, special devotionals, Jubilees, retreats, etc... Begin to rearrange schedule to come to all the meetings of the body.
		</original>
		<translated>
			Você deve ir a todas as reuniões do corpo: Cultos de domingo e meio da semana, bate-papo bíblico, devocionais especiais, jubileus, retiros, etc. Comece a reorganizar sua agenda para estar em todas as reuniões do corpo.
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="62" desc="">
		<original>
			Contribution
		</original>
		<translated>
			Contribuição
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="63" desc="">
		<original>
			1 Corinthians 16:1-2: Paul gave a plan to set aside money on the first day of the week for the Lord and the needs of His people. Our plan is to set aside a tenth of our pay as the beginning guideline of our sacrifice on Sundays to meet the ministry needs. Benevolent offerings are given at Midweek Services.
		</original>
		<translated>
			1 Coríntios 16:1-2 Paulo estabeleceu um plano para separar dinheiro no primeiro dia da semana para o Senhor e as necessidades de seu povo. Nosso plano é separar a décima parte do nosso salário como a diretriz inicial do nosso sacrifício aos domingos para atender as necessidades do ministério. Ofertas benevolentes são dadas nos cultos de meio de semana.
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="true" scripturekey="1-corinthians-16-1-2">
			<original>
				1 Corinthians 16:1-2
			</original>
			<translated>
				1 Coríntios 16:1-2
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="64" desc="">
		<original>
			2 Corinthians 9:6-8: Giving should be from a "cheerful" heart — not under compulsion. God blesses you when you give generously.
		</original>
		<translated>
			2 Coríntios 9:6-8: O ato de dar deve vir de um coração "alegre" - e não sob compulsão. Deus o abençoa quando você sacrifica.
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="true" scripturekey="2-corinthians-9-6-8">
			<original>
				2 Corinthians 9:6-8
			</original>
			<translated>
				2 Coríntios 9:6-8
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>
	
	<!--

	<phrase id="" desc="">
		<original>
			
		</original>
		<translated>
			
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="true">
			<original>
				
			</original>
			<translated>
				
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="" desc="">
		<original>
			
		</original>
		<translated>
			
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	-->

</content>
