<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<scripture key="matthew-6-25-34" lang="en" version="niv" edition="1984">
	<passage title="Matthew 6:25-34" book="Matthew" book-en="Matthew">
		<chapter number="6" number-en="6">
			<verse number="25" number-en="25" jesuswords="true">
				<p class="scripture-heading">
					Do Not Worry
				</p>
				<span class="jesuswords">Therefore I tell you, do not worry about your life, what you will eat or drink; or about your body, what you will wear. Is not life more important than food, and the body more important than clothes?</span>
			</verse>
			<verse number="26" number-en="26" jesuswords="true">
				<span class="jesuswords">Look at the birds of the air; they do not sow or reap or store away in barns, and yet your heavenly Father feeds them. Are you not much more valuable than they?</span>
			</verse>
			<verse number="27" number-en="27" jesuswords="true">
				<span class="jesuswords">Who of you by worrying can add a single hour to his life?</span>
			</verse>
			<verse number="28" number-en="28" jesuswords="true">
				<span class="jesuswords">And why do you worry about clothes? See how the lilies of the field grow. They do not labor or spin.</span>
			</verse>
			<verse number="29" number-en="29" jesuswords="true">
				<span class="jesuswords">Yet I tell you that not even Solomon in all his splendor was dressed like one of these.</span>
			</verse>
			<verse number="30" number-en="30" jesuswords="true">
				<span class="jesuswords">If that is how God clothes the grass of the field, which is here today and tomorrow is thrown into the fire, will he not much more clothe you, O you of little faith?</span>
			</verse>
			<verse number="31" number-en="31" jesuswords="true">
				<span class="jesuswords">So do not worry, saying, 'What shall we eat?' or 'What shall we drink?' or 'What shall we wear?'</span>
			</verse>
			<verse number="32" number-en="32" jesuswords="true">
				<span class="jesuswords">For the pagans run after all these things, and your heavenly Father knows that you need them.</span>
			</verse>
			<verse number="33" number-en="33" jesuswords="true">
				<span class="jesuswords">But seek first his kingdom and his righteousness, and all these things will be given to you as well.</span>
			</verse>
			<verse number="34" number-en="34" jesuswords="true">
				<span class="jesuswords">Therefore do not worry about tomorrow, for tomorrow will worry about itself. Each day has enough trouble of its own.</span>
			</verse>
		</chapter>
	</passage>
</scripture>

<!--
			<verse number="" number-en="">
				
			</verse>
			<verse number="" number-en="">
				<p class="scripture-heading">
					Heading text
				</p>
			</verse>
-->
