<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<scripture key="hebrews-5-11-6-6" lang="en" version="niv" edition="1984">
	<passage title="Hebrews 5:11 - 6:6" book="Hebrews" book-en="Hebrews">
		<chapter number="5" number-en="5">
			<verse number="11" number-en="11">
				<p class="scripture-heading">
					Warning Against Falling Away
				</p>
				We have much to say about this, but it is hard to explain because you are slow to learn.
			</verse>
			<verse number="12" number-en="12">
				In fact, though by this time you ought to be teachers, you need someone to teach you the elementary truths of God's word all over again. You need milk, not solid food!
			</verse>
			<verse number="13" number-en="13">
				Anyone who lives on milk, being still an infant, is not acquainted with the teaching about righteousness.
			</verse>
			<verse number="14" number-en="14">
				But solid food is for the mature, who by constant use have trained themselves to distinguish good from evil.
			</verse>
		</chapter>
		<chapter number="6" number-en="6">
			<verse number="1" number-en="1">
				Therefore let us leave the elementary teachings about Christ and go on to maturity, not laying again the foundation of repentance from acts that lead to death, and of faith in God,
			</verse>
			<verse number="2" number-en="2">
				instruction about baptisms, the laying on of hands, the resurrection of the dead, and eternal judgment.
			</verse>
			<verse number="3" number-en="3">
				And God permitting, we will do so.
			</verse>
			<verse number="4" number-en="4">
				It is impossible for those who have once been enlightened, who have tasted the heavenly gift, who have shared in the Holy Spirit,
			</verse>
			<verse number="5" number-en="5">
				who have tasted the goodness of the word of God and the powers of the coming age,
			</verse>
			<verse number="6" number-en="6">
				if they fall away, to be brought back to repentance, because to their loss they are crucifying the Son of God all over again and subjecting him to public disgrace.
			</verse>
		</chapter>
	</passage>
</scripture>

<!--
			<verse number="" number-en="">
				
			</verse>
			<verse number="" number-en="">
				<p class="scripture-heading">
					Heading text
				</p>
			</verse>
-->
