<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<scripture key="acts-10" lang="en" version="niv" edition="1984">
	<passage title="Acts 10" book="Acts" book-en="Acts">
		<chapter number="10" number-en="10">
			<verse number="1" number-en="1">
				<p class="scripture-heading">
					Cornelius Calls for Peter
				</p>
				At Caesarea there was a man named Cornelius, a centurion in what was known as the Italian Regiment.
			</verse>
			<verse number="2" number-en="2">
				He and all his family were devout and God-fearing; he gave generously to those in need and prayed to God regularly.
			</verse>
			<verse number="3" number-en="3">
				One day at about three in the afternoon he had a vision. He distinctly saw an angel of God, who came to him and said, "Cornelius!"
			</verse>
			<verse number="4" number-en="4">
				Cornelius stared at him in fear. "What is it, Lord?" he asked. The angel answered, "Your prayers and gifts to the poor have come up as a memorial offering before God.
			</verse>
			<verse number="5" number-en="5">
				Now send men to Joppa to bring back a man named Simon who is called Peter.
			</verse>
			<verse number="6" number-en="6">
				He is staying with Simon the tanner, whose house is by the sea."
			</verse>
			<verse number="7" number-en="7">
				When the angel who spoke to him had gone, Cornelius called two of his servants and a devout soldier who was one of his attendants.
			</verse>
			<verse number="8" number-en="8">
				He told them everything that had happened and sent them to Joppa.
			</verse>
			<verse number="9" number-en="9">
				<p class="scripture-heading">
					Peter's Vision
				</p>
				About noon the following day as they were on their journey and approaching the city, Peter went up on the roof to pray.
			</verse>
			<verse number="10" number-en="10">
				He became hungry and wanted something to eat, and while the meal was being prepared, he fell into a trance.
			</verse>
			<verse number="11" number-en="11">
				He saw heaven opened and something like a large sheet being let down to earth by its four corners.
			</verse>
			<verse number="12" number-en="12">
				It contained all kinds of four-footed animals, as well as reptiles of the earth and birds of the air.
			</verse>
			<verse number="13" number-en="13">
				Then a voice told him, "Get up, Peter. Kill and eat."
			</verse>
			<verse number="14" number-en="14">
				"Surely not, Lord!" Peter replied. "I have never eaten anything impure or unclean."
			</verse>
			<verse number="15" number-en="15">
				The voice spoke to him a second time, "Do not call anything impure that God has made clean."
			</verse>
			<verse number="16" number-en="16">
				This happened three times, and immediately the sheet was taken back to heaven.
			</verse>
			<verse number="17" number-en="17">
				While Peter was wondering about the meaning of the vision, the men sent by Cornelius found out where Simon's house was and stopped at the gate.
			</verse>
			<verse number="18" number-en="18">
				They called out, asking if Simon who was known as Peter was staying there.
			</verse>
			<verse number="19" number-en="19">
				While Peter was still thinking about the vision, the Spirit said to him, "Simon, three men are looking for you.
			</verse>
			<verse number="20" number-en="20">
				So get up and go downstairs. Do not hesitate to go with them, for I have sent them."
			</verse>
			<verse number="21" number-en="21">
				Peter went down and said to the men, "I'm the one you're looking for. Why have you come?"
			</verse>
			<verse number="22" number-en="22">
				The men replied, "We have come from Cornelius the centurion. He is a righteous and God-fearing man, who is respected by all the Jewish people. A holy angel told him to have you come to his house so that he could hear what you have to say."
			</verse>
			<verse number="23" number-en="23">
				Then Peter invited the men into the house to be his guests. 
				<p class="scripture-heading">
					Peter at Cornelius' House
				</p>
				The next day Peter started out with them, and some of the brothers from Joppa went along.
			</verse>
			<verse number="24" number-en="24">
				The following day he arrived in Caesarea. Cornelius was expecting them and had called together his relatives and close friends.
			</verse>
			<verse number="25" number-en="25">
				As Peter entered the house, Cornelius met him and fell at his feet in reverence.
			</verse>
			<verse number="26" number-en="26">
				But Peter made him get up. "Stand up," he said, "I am only a man myself."
			</verse>
			<verse number="27" number-en="27">
				Talking with him, Peter went inside and found a large gathering of people.
			</verse>
			<verse number="28" number-en="28">
				He said to them: "You are well aware that it is against our law for a Jew to associate with a Gentile or visit him. But God has shown me that I should not call any man impure or unclean.
			</verse>
			<verse number="29" number-en="29">
				So when I was sent for, I came without raising any objection. May I ask why you sent for me?"
			</verse>
			<verse number="30" number-en="30">
				Cornelius answered: "Four days ago I was in my house praying at this hour, at three in the afternoon. Suddenly a man in shining clothes stood before me
			</verse>
			<verse number="31" number-en="31">
				and said, 'Cornelius, God has heard your prayer and remembered your gifts to the poor.
			</verse>
			<verse number="32" number-en="32">
				Send to Joppa for Simon who is called Peter. He is a guest in the home of Simon the tanner, who lives by the sea.'
			</verse>
			<verse number="33" number-en="33">
				So I sent for you immediately, and it was good of you to come. Now we are all here in the presence of God to listen to everything the Lord has commanded you to tell us."
			</verse>
			<verse number="34" number-en="34">
				Then Peter began to speak: "I now realize how true it is that God does not show favoritism
			</verse>
			<verse number="35" number-en="35">
				but accepts men from every nation who fear him and do what is right.
			</verse>
			<verse number="36" number-en="36">
				You know the message God sent to the people of Israel, telling the good news of peace through Jesus Christ, who is Lord of all.
			</verse>
			<verse number="37" number-en="37">
				You know what has happened throughout Judea, beginning in Galilee after the baptism that John preached —
			</verse>
			<verse number="38" number-en="38">
				how God anointed Jesus of Nazareth with the Holy Spirit and power, and how he went around doing good and healing all who were under the power of the devil, because God was with him.
			</verse>
			<verse number="39" number-en="39">
				We are witnesses of everything he did in the country of the Jews and in Jerusalem. They killed him by hanging him on a tree,
			</verse>
			<verse number="40" number-en="40">
				but God raised him from the dead on the third day and caused him to be seen.
			</verse>
			<verse number="41" number-en="41">
				He was not seen by all the people, but by witnesses whom God had already chosen — by us who ate and drank with him after he rose from the dead.
			</verse>
			<verse number="42" number-en="42">
				He commanded us to preach to the people and to testify that he is the one whom God appointed as judge of the living and the dead.
			</verse>
			<verse number="43" number-en="43">
				All the prophets testify about him that everyone who believes in him receives forgiveness of sins through his name."
			</verse>
			<verse number="44" number-en="44">
				While Peter was still speaking these words, the Holy Spirit came on all who heard the message.
			</verse>
			<verse number="45" number-en="45">
				The circumcised believers who had come with Peter were astonished that the gift of the Holy Spirit had been poured out even on the Gentiles.
			</verse>
			<verse number="46" number-en="46">
				For they heard them speaking in tongues and praising God. Then Peter said,
			</verse>
			<verse number="47" number-en="47">
				"Can anyone keep these people from being baptized with water? They have received the Holy Spirit just as we have."
			</verse>
			<verse number="48" number-en="48">
				So he ordered that they be baptized in the name of Jesus Christ. Then they asked Peter to stay with them for a few days.
			</verse>
		</chapter>
	</passage>
</scripture>

<!--
			<verse number="" number-en="">
				
			</verse>
			<verse number="" number-en="">
				<p class="scripture-heading">
					Heading text
				</p>
			</verse>
-->
