<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<scripture key="1-corinthians-11-23-32" lang="en" version="niv" edition="1984">
	<passage title="1 Corinthians 11:23-32" book="1 Corinthians" book-en="1 Corinthians">
		<chapter number="11" number-en="11">
			<verse number="23" number-en="23">
				For I received from the Lord what I also passed on to you: The Lord Jesus, on the night he was betrayed, took bread,
			</verse>
			<verse number="24" number-en="24" jesuswords="true">
				and when he had given thanks, he broke it and said, "<span class="jesuswords">This is my body, which is for you; do this in remembrance of me.</span>"
			</verse>
			<verse number="25" number-en="25" jesuswords="true">
				In the same way, after supper he took the cup, saying, "<span class="jesuswords">This cup is the new covenant in my blood; do this, whenever you drink it, in remembrance of me.</span>"
			</verse>
			<verse number="26" number-en="26">
				For whenever you eat this bread and drink this cup, you proclaim the Lord's death until he comes.
			</verse>
			<verse number="27" number-en="27">
				Therefore, whoever eats the bread or drinks the cup of the Lord in an unworthy manner will be guilty of sinning against the body and blood of the Lord.
			</verse>
			<verse number="28" number-en="28">
				A man ought to examine himself before he eats of the bread and drinks of the cup.
			</verse>
			<verse number="29" number-en="29">
				For anyone who eats and drinks without recognizing the body of the Lord eats and drinks judgment on himself.
			</verse>
			<verse number="30" number-en="30">
				That is why many among you are weak and sick, and a number of you have fallen asleep.
			</verse>
			<verse number="31" number-en="31">
				But if we judged ourselves, we would not come under judgment.
			</verse>
			<verse number="32" number-en="32">
				When we are judged by the Lord, we are being disciplined so that we will not be condemned with the world.
			</verse>
		</chapter>
	</passage>
</scripture>

<!--
			<verse number="" number-en="">
				
			</verse>
			<verse number="" number-en="">
				<p class="scripture-heading">
					Heading text
				</p>
			</verse>
-->
