<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<content key="memory-scriptures" lang-original="en" lang-translated="pt" last-updated="2019-02-18" last-updated-by="Waldir Caro" last-updated-by-email="edisone11.fc@gmail.com" created="2018-09-29" created-by="Jason McNeill" created-by-email="vrtjason@gmail.com">
	
	<phrase id="1" desc="title">
		<original>
			Memory Scriptures
		</original>
		<translated>
			Escrituras a Decorar
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="2" desc="">
		<original>
			"For I know the plans I have for you," declares the LORD, "plans to prosper you and not to harm you, plans to give you hope and a future."
		</original>
		<translated>
			"Porque sou eu que conheço os planos que tenho para vocês", diz o Senhor, "planos de fazê-los prosperar e não de lhes causar dano, planos de dar-lhes esperança e um futuro."
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="3" desc="">
		<original>
			Jeremiah 29:11
		</original>
		<translated>
			Jeremias 29:11
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="4" desc="">
		<original>
			But seek first his kingdom and his righteousness, and all these things will be given to you as well.
		</original>
		<translated>
			Busquem, pois, em primeiro lugar o Reino de Deus e a sua justiça, e todas essas coisas lhes serão acrescentadas.
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="5" desc="">
		<original>
			Matthew 6:33
		</original>
		<translated>
			Mateus 6:33
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="6" desc="">
		<original>
			To the Jews who had believed him, Jesus said, "If you hold to my teaching, you are really my disciples. Then you will know the truth, and the truth will set you free."
		</original>
		<translated>
			Disse Jesus aos judeus que haviam crido nele: "Se vocês permanecerem firmes na minha palavra, verdadeiramente serão meus discípulos. E conhecerão a verdade, e a verdade os libertará".
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="7" desc="">
		<original>
			John 8:31-32
		</original>
		<translated>
			João 8:31-32
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="8" desc="">
		<original>
			I can do everything through him who gives me strength.
		</original>
		<translated>
			Tudo posso naquele que me fortalece.
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="9" desc="">
		<original>
			Philippians 4:13
		</original>
		<translated>
			Filipenses 4:13
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="10" desc="">
		<original>
			"Come, follow me," Jesus said, "and I will make you fishers of men."
		</original>
		<translated>
			E disse Jesus: "Sigam-me, e eu os farei pescadores de homens".
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="11" desc="">
		<original>
			Mark 1:17
		</original>
		<translated>
			Marcos 1:17
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="12" desc="">
		<original>
			A new command I give you: Love one another. As I have loved you, so you must love one another. By this all men will know that you are my disciples, if you love one another.
		</original>
		<translated>
			"Um novo mandamento lhes dou: Amem-se uns aos outros. Como eu os amei, vocês devem amar-se uns aos outros. Com isso todos saberão que vocês são meus discípulos, se vocês se amarem uns aos outros".
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="13" desc="">
		<original>
			John 13:34-35
		</original>
		<translated>
			João 13:34-35
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="14" desc="">
		<original>
			Peter replied, 'Repent and be baptized, every one of you, in the name of Jesus Christ for the forgiveness of your sins. And you will receive the gift of the Holy Spirit.
		</original>
		<translated>
			Pedro respondeu: "Arrependam-se, e cada um de vocês seja batizado em nome de Jesus Cristo, para perdão dos seus pecados, e receberão o dom do Espírito Santo.
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="15" desc="">
		<original>
			Acts 2:38
		</original>
		<translated>
			Atos 2:38
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="16" desc="">
		<original>
			Rejoice in the Lord always. I will say it again: Rejoice!
		</original>
		<translated>
			Alegrem-se sempre no Senhor. Novamente direi: alegrem-se!
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="17" desc="">
		<original>
			Philippians 4:4
		</original>
		<translated>
			Filipenses 4:4
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="18" desc="">
		<original>
			The soul who sins is the one who will die. The son will not share the guilt of the father, nor will the father share the guilt of the son. The righteousness of the righteous man will be credited to him, and the wickedness of the wicked will be charged against him.
		</original>
		<translated>
			Aquele que pecar é que morrerá. O filho não levará a culpa do pai, nem o pai levará a culpa do filho. A justiça do justo lhe será creditada, e a impiedade do ímpio lhe será cobrada.
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="19" desc="">
		<original>
			Ezekiel 18:20
		</original>
		<translated>
			Ezequiel 18:20
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="20" desc="">
		<original>
			But even if we or an angel from heaven should preach a gospel other than the one we preached to you, let him be eternally condemned!
		</original>
		<translated>
			Mas ainda que nós ou um anjo do céu pregue um evangelho diferente daquele que lhes pregamos, que seja amaldiçoado!
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="21" desc="">
		<original>
			Galatians 1:8
		</original>
		<translated>
			Gálatas 1:8
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="22" desc="">
		<original>
			Jesus replied: "Love the Lord your God with all your heart and with all your soul and with all your mind." This is the first and greatest commandment. And the second is like it: "Love your neighbor as yourself."
		</original>
		<translated>
			Respondeu Jesus: "‘Ame o Senhor, o seu Deus de todo o seu coração, de toda a sua alma e de todo o seu entendimento’. Este é o primeiro e maior mandamento. E o segundo é semelhante a ele: ‘Ame o seu próximo como a si mesmo’.
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="23" desc="">
		<original>
			Matthew 22:37-39
		</original>
		<translated>
			Mateus 22:37-39
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="24" desc="">
		<original>
			This is to my Father's glory, that you bear much fruit, showing yourselves to be my disciples.
		</original>
		<translated>
			Meu Pai é glorificado pelo fato de vocês darem muito fruto; e assim serão meus discípulos.
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="25" desc="">
		<original>
			John 15:8
		</original>
		<translated>
			João 15:8
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="26" desc="">
		<original>
			Then Jesus came to them and said, "All authority in heaven and on earth has been given to me. Therefore go and make disciples of all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father and of the Son and of the Holy Spirit, and teaching them to obey everything I have commanded you. And surely I am with you always, to the very end of the age."
		</original>
		<translated>
			Então, Jesus aproximou-se deles e disse: "Foi-me dada toda a autoridade no céu e na terra. Portanto, vão e façam discípulos de todas as nações, batizando-os em nome do Pai e do Filho e do Espírito Santo, ensinando-os a obedecer a tudo o que eu lhes ordenei. E eu estarei sempre com vocês, até o fim dos tempos".
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="27" desc="">
		<original>
			Matthew 28:18-20
		</original>
		<translated>
			Mateus 28:18-20
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="28" desc="">
		<original>
			For the Son of Man came to seek and to save the lost.
		</original>
		<translated>
			Pois o Filho do homem veio buscar e salvar o que estava perdido".
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="29" desc="">
		<original>
			Luke 19:10
		</original>
		<translated>
			Lucas 19:10
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="30" desc="">
		<original>
			And let us consider how we may spur one another on toward love and good deeds. Let us not give up meeting together, as some are in the habit of doing, but let us encourage one another — and all the more as you see the Day approaching.
		</original>
		<translated>
			E consideremo-nos uns aos outros para incentivar-nos ao amor e às boas obras. Não deixemos de reunir-nos como igreja, segundo o costume de alguns, mas encorajemo-nos uns aos outros, ainda mais quando vocês vêem que se aproxima o Dia.
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="31" desc="">
		<original>
			Hebrews 10:24-25
		</original>
		<translated>
			Hebreus 10:24-25
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="32" desc="">
		<original>
			If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just and will forgive us our sins and purify us from all unrighteousness.
		</original>
		<translated>
			Se confessarmos os nossos pecados, ele é fiel e justo para perdoar os nossos pecados e nos purificar de toda injustiça.
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="33" desc="">
		<original>
			1 John 1:9
		</original>
		<translated>
			1 João 1:9
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="34" desc="">
		<original>
			See to it that no one misses the grace of God and that no bitter root grows up to cause trouble and defile many.
		</original>
		<translated>
			Cuidem que ninguém se exclua da graça de Deus. Que nenhuma raiz de amargura brote e cause perturbação, contaminando a muitos.
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="35" desc="">
		<original>
			Hebrews 12:15
		</original>
		<translated>
			Hebreus 12:15
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="36" desc="">
		<original>
			Obey your leaders and submit to their authority. They keep watch over you as men who must give an account. Obey them so that their work will be a joy, not a burden, for that would be of no advantage to you.
		</original>
		<translated>
			Obedeçam aos seus líderes e submetam-se à autoridade deles. Eles cuidam de vocês como quem deve prestar contas. Obedeçam-lhes, para que o trabalho deles seja uma alegria e não um peso, pois isso não seria proveitoso para vocês.
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="37" desc="">
		<original>
			Hebrews 13:17
		</original>
		<translated>
			Hebreus 13:17
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<!--

	<phrase id="" desc="">
		<original>
			
		</original>
		<translated>
			
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="true">
			<original>
				
			</original>
			<translated>
				
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="" desc="">
		<original>
			
		</original>
		<translated>
			
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	-->

</content>
