<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<scripture key="hebrews-10-23-35" lang="en" version="niv" edition="1984">
	<passage title="Hebrews 10:23-35" book="Hebrews" book-en="Hebrews">
		<chapter number="10" number-en="10">
			<verse number="23" number-en="23">
				Let us hold unswervingly to the hope we profess, for he who promised is faithful.
			</verse>
			<verse number="24" number-en="24">
				And let us consider how we may spur one another on toward love and good deeds.
			</verse>
			<verse number="25" number-en="25">
				Let us not give up meeting together, as some are in the habit of doing, but let us encourage one another — and all the more as you see the Day approaching.
			</verse>
			<verse number="26" number-en="26">
				If we deliberately keep on sinning after we have received the knowledge of the truth, no sacrifice for sins is left,
			</verse>
			<verse number="27" number-en="27">
				but only a fearful expectation of judgment and of raging fire that will consume the enemies of God.
			</verse>
			<verse number="28" number-en="28">
				Anyone who rejected the law of Moses died without mercy on the testimony of two or three witnesses.
			</verse>
			<verse number="29" number-en="29">
				How much more severely do you think a man deserves to be punished who has trampled the Son of God under foot, who has treated as an unholy thing the blood of the covenant that sanctified him, and who has insulted the Spirit of grace?
			</verse>
			<verse number="30" number-en="30" scripturequote="true">
				For we know him who said, <span class="scripturequote">"It is mine to avenge; I will repay,"</span> and again, <span class="scripturequote">"The LORD will judge his people."</span>
			</verse>
			<verse number="31" number-en="31">
				It is a dreadful thing to fall into the hands of the living God.
			</verse>
			<verse number="32" number-en="32">
				Remember those earlier days after you had received the light, when you stood your ground in a great contest in the face of suffering.
			</verse>
			<verse number="33" number-en="33">
				Sometimes you were publicly exposed to insult and persecution; at other times you stood side by side with those who were so treated.
			</verse>
			<verse number="34" number-en="34">
				You sympathized with those in prison and joyfully accepted the confiscation of your property, because you knew that you yourselves had better and lasting possessions.
			</verse>
			<verse number="35" number-en="35">
				So do not throw away your confidence; it will be richly rewarded.
			</verse>
		</chapter>
	</passage>
</scripture>

<!--
			<verse number="" number-en="">
				
			</verse>
			<verse number="" number-en="">
				<p class="scripture-heading">
					Heading text
				</p>
			</verse>
-->
