<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<content key="introduction" lang-original="en" lang-translated="es" last-updated="2018-09-29" last-updated-by="Aurora McNeill" last-updated-by-email="auroramcneill@hotmail.com" created="2018-09-29" created-by="Jason McNeill" created-by-email="vrtjason@gmail.com">
	
	<phrase id="1" desc="title">
		<original>
			Introduction
		</original>
		<translated>
			Introducción
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="2" desc="">
		<original>
			"For when by reason of the time you ought to be teachers, you... need to have someone teach you the rudiments of the first principles of the oracles of God... Therefore leaving the doctrine of the first principles of Christ, let us press on to perfection — not laying again a foundation... of faith toward God, of the teaching of baptisms, of laying on of hands, of resurrection of the dead and of eternal judgment. This will we do!"
		</original>
		<translated>
			"En realidad, a estas alturas ya deberían ser maestros... y sin embargo necesitan que alguien vuelva a enseñarles las verdades más elementales de la palabra de Dios. Dicho de otro modo, necesitan leche en vez de alimento sólido. Por eso, dejando a un lado las enseñanzas elementales acerca de Cristo, avancemos hacia la madurez. No volvamos a poner los fundamentos, tales como el arrepentimiento de las obras que conducen a la muerte, la fe en Dios, la instrucción sobre bautismos, la imposición de manos, la resurrección de los muertos y el juicio eterno. Así procederemos, si Dios lo permite."
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="3" desc="">
		<original>
			Hebrews 5:12; 6:1-3 (WEV)
		</original>
		<translated>
			Hebrews 5:12; 6:1-3 (Nueva Versión Internacional)
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="false" href="">
			<original>
				Hebrews 5:12; 6:1-3
			</original>
			<translated>
				 Hebreos 5:12; 6:1-3
			</translated>
		</change>
		<change bold="false" italic="true" modal="false" href="">
			<original>
				(WEV)
			</original>
			<translated>
				Nueva Versión Internacional
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="4" desc="">
		<original>
			Originally, the First Principle Studies were written in 1980, while I served the Lord during the formative early days of the Boston Church of Christ. They were revised in 2003 and 2006 to meet the needs and to confront the challenges of the Portland International Church of Christ. In Los Angeles in 2009 and 2012, I made a few more modifications. As of today, these same First Principles Studies are being taught to all the new disciples of the City of Angels International Christian Church. God has greatly blessed these lessons as they have been translated into over 20 languages around the world. May the Lord continue to "solidify, unify and multiply" sold-out disciples everywhere for the evangelization of all the nations in this generation! And to God be the glory! 
		</original>
		<translated>
			Originalmente, los estudios de los Principios Básicos fueron escritos en 1980, mientras servía yo en los primeros días de la Iglesia de Cristo en Boston. Fueron revisados en los años 2003 y 2006 para suplir las necesidades y enfrentar los retos de la Iglesia de Cristo Internacional en Pórtland. En Los Angeles en los años 2009 y 2012, le hice algunas modificasiones. Hasta el dia de hoy, los Principios Básicos estudios son los mismos y se les han enseñado a todos los discipulos nuevos de la Iglesia Christiana International de la ciudad de Los Angeles. Dios ha bendecido enormemente estas lecciones ya que se han traducido a más de 20 idiomas en todo el mundo. ¡Que el Señor continúe "solidificando, unificando y multiplicando" discípulos comprometidos en todas partes para la evangelización de todas las naciones en esta generación! ¡Y toda la gloria sea de Dios!
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="false" href="http://www.caicc.net/">
			<original>
				City of Angels International Christian Church
			</original>
			<translated>
				Iglesia Christiana International de la ciudad de Los Angeles
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="5" desc="">
		<original>
			Dr. Kip McKean
		</original>
		<translated>
			Dr. Kip McKean
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="6" desc="">
		<original>
			July 1, 2014
		</original>
		<translated>
			1 de julio de 2014
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<!--
	<phrase id="" desc="">
		<original>
			
		</original>
		<translated>
			
		</translated>
	</phrase>



	<phrase id="" desc="">
		<original>
			
		</original>
		<translated>
			
		</translated>
		<change bold="false" italic="false" modal="false" href="">
			<original>
				
			</original>
			<translated>

			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	-->

</content>
