<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<content key="introduction" lang-original="en" lang-translated="es" last-updated="2020-02-15" last-updated-by="Jason McNeill" last-updated-by-email="vrtjason@gmail.com" created="2018-09-29" created-by="Jason McNeill" created-by-email="vrtjason@gmail.com">
	
	<phrase id="1" desc="title">
		<original>
			Introduction
		</original>
		<translated>
			Introducción
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="2" desc="">
		<original>
			"For when by reason of the time you ought to be teachers, you... need to have someone teach you the rudiments of the first principles of the oracles of God... Therefore leaving the doctrine of the first principles of Christ, let us press on to perfection — not laying again a foundation... of faith toward God, of the teaching of baptisms, of laying on of hands, of resurrection of the dead and of eternal judgment. This will we do!"
		</original>
		<translated>
			“En realidad a estas alturas ya deberían ser maestros... necesitan que alguien vuelva a enseñarles las verdades más elementales [Principios Básicos] de la Palabra de Dios... Por eso, dejando a un lado las enseñanzas elementales [Principios Básicos] acerca de Cristo, avancemos hacia la madurez. No volvamos a poner los fundamentos, tales como... la fe en Dios, la instrucción sobre bautismos, la imposición de manos, la resurrección de los muertos y el juicio eterno. Así procederemos, si Dios lo permite.”
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="3" desc="">
		<original>
			Hebrews 5:12; 6:1-3 (WEV)
		</original>
		<translated>
			Hebreos 5:12; 6:1-3 (Nueva Versión Internacional)
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="false">
			<original>
				Hebrews 5:12; 6:1-3
			</original>
			<translated>
				Hebreos 5:12; 6:1-3
			</translated>
		</change>
		<change bold="false" italic="true" modal="false">
			<original>
				(WEV)
			</original>
			<translated>
				(Nueva Versión Internacional)
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="4" desc="">
		<original>
			Originally, the First Principle Studies were written in 1980, while I served the Lord during the formative early days of the Boston Church of Christ. They were revised in 2003 and 2006 to meet the needs and to confront the challenges of the Portland International Church of Christ. In Los Angeles in 2009 and 2012, I made a few more modifications. As of today, these same First Principles Studies are being taught to all the new disciples of the City of Angels International Christian Church. God has greatly blessed these lessons as they have been translated into over 20 languages around the world. May the Lord continue to "solidify, unify and multiply" sold-out disciples everywhere for the evangelization of all the nations in this generation! And to God be the glory! 
		</original>
		<translated>
			Los estudios de Principios Básicos fueron escritos originalmente en 1980, mientras yo servía al Señor durante los primeros días de formación de la Iglesia de Cristo de Boston. Estos fueron revisados en 2003 y 2006, para suplir las necesidades y enfrentar los desafíos de la Iglesia de Cristo Internacional de Portland. Recientemente, después de dos años de liderar en Los Ángeles, hice algunas modificaciones adicionales. Desde entonces, estos mismos estudios de Principios Básicos se enseñan a todos los nuevos discípulos de la Iglesia Cristiana Internacional de la Ciudad de Los Ángeles. Dios ha bendecido grandemente estas lecciones que han sido traducidas a más de veinte idiomas alrededor del mundo.
			<br />
			<br />¡Que el Señor continúe “solidificando, unificando y multiplicando” a los discípulos totalmente comprometidos en todo el mundo, para que sigan evangelizando a todas las naciones en esta generación!
			<br />
			<br />¡Y a Dios sea toda la gloria!
		</translated>
		<change bold="true" italic="false" modal="false" href="http://www.caicc.net/">
			<original>
				City of Angels International Christian Church
			</original>
			<translated>
				Iglesia Cristiana Internacional de la Ciudad de Los Ángeles
			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="5" desc="">
		<original>
			Dr. Kip McKean
		</original>
		<translated>
			Dr. Kip McKean
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<phrase id="6" desc="">
		<original>
			July 1, 2014
		</original>
		<translated>
			Julio 1 de 2014
		</translated>
	</phrase>

	<!--
	<phrase id="" desc="">
		<original>
			
		</original>
		<translated>
			
		</translated>
	</phrase>



	<phrase id="" desc="">
		<original>
			
		</original>
		<translated>
			
		</translated>
		<change bold="false" italic="false" modal="false">
			<original>
				
			</original>
			<translated>

			</translated>
		</change>
	</phrase>

	-->

</content>
